move.
動く。
We are currently at dioxide research committee.
私たちは現在、二酸化炭素研究委員会にいます。
The TWA will start learning how to use the flooding to sec naive in stepping up a practicalicked recharge.
TWAは、実用的な再充電を強化するために、洪水を利用する方法を学び始めるでしょう。
Hello everyone
こんにちは、みんな
Welcome to one breakfast
ワンブレックファストへようこそ
I want to represent our Vice President Huang Jingxin first.
まず私が副大統領の黄景新を代表したいと思います。
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Because he was supposed to host
彼が司会をすることになっていたので、
he is a little unwell
彼は少し体調が悪いです
So I'm temporarily assigned to host
ということで、一時的にホストを任されることになりました
Again, I want to remind everyone that
もう一度皆さんに思い出していただきたいのですが、
from the last speech
最後のスピーチから
Our present feast of knowledge
私たちの現在の知識の饗宴
Live broadcast every time
毎回生放送
webcast
ウェブキャスト
So if it is not convenient for you to come to the scene in the future
したがって、今後現場に来るのが都合が悪い場合は、
You can watch it at home or online
自宅でもネットでも視聴できる
I hope you can tell your friends
お友達にも教えていただけると幸いです
I also hope that more people
また、もっと多くの人が来てくれることを願っています
able to take advantage of such opportunities
そのような機会を活用できる
Come enjoy some of our great presentations
素晴らしいプレゼンテーションをぜひお楽しみください
Then I will make an announcement
それでは発表させていただきます
I'm afraid I'll forget it later
後で忘れてしまいそうで怖い
next month
来月
Feast of Knowledge in December
12月の知識の饗宴
by this of our hospital
当院のこれにより
History and Institute
歴史と研究所
Ten Signs of Fortune
幸運の十の兆し
speak for us
私たちのために話してください
images of historical memory
歴史的記憶のイメージ
From Digital Three Kingdoms to Dongpo
デジタル三国志から東坡へ
I have stabbing arms
腕が刺さってます
I hope everyone can come to participate next time
次回はぜひ皆さんも参加していただければと思います
Today I am very happy to have this opportunity to introduce my old colleagues
今日は昔の同僚を紹介する機会を持ててとても嬉しいです
Mr. Chen Yizhuang, an old colleague of more than 20 years
20年以上の古い同僚であるチェン・イーチュアン先生
Dr. Yizhuang Chen is in our Institute of Biomedical Sciences
Yizhuang Chen 博士は私たちの生物医科学研究所にいます
He is a graduate of National Taiwan University Department of Agrochemistry
彼は国立台湾大学農芸化学科を卒業しています。
Then I went to Massachusetts Zhouli University in the United States to study for a Ph.D.
その後、博士号取得のために米国のマサチューセッツ州立大学に留学しました。
It only took four years
たったの4年しかかかりませんでした
Then went to Harvard University as a postdoctoral fellow
その後ハーバード大学に博士研究員として留学
only took two years
たった2年かかった
Then I returned to Taiwan to join the Biomedical Institute
その後台湾に戻り、生物医学研究所に参加しました。
Then his research at the Institute of Biomedical Sciences has always been related to neurodegeneration and drug development
その後、生物医学研究所での彼の研究は常に神経変性と医薬品開発に関連していました。
Then today we can hear his wonderful speech in this regard
そして今日、私たちはこの点に関する彼の素晴らしいスピーチを聞くことができます
His research has been outstanding
彼の研究は傑出したものでした
so he won many awards
それで彼は多くの賞を受賞しました
He was selected as one of our top ten outstanding young women
彼は、優秀な若い女性トップ 10 の 1 人に選ばれました。
Top Ten Lifted Youth
持ち上げられた青少年トップ 10
Won the Academia Sinica Young Researcher's Writing Award
中央研究院若手研究者執筆賞を受賞
Won the dismissal award from the National Science Council of the Executive Yuan three times
行政院国家科学会議から罷免賞を3回受賞
If you graduate three times, you can't get it again.
3回卒業したら次は卒業できない
As a special researcher of the Ministry of Science and Technology
科学技術省特別研究員として
Then I got Dr. Du Congming's commemorative speech
そして杜聡明先生の記念講演を頂きました。
Li Tiande Medical Science and Technology Award
李天徳医学科学技術賞
a lot of
たくさんの
In addition to his academic research
学術研究に加えて、
He has also done a lot of service to our academic community
彼は私たちの学術コミュニティにも多大な貢献をしてくれました
Then he served in the National Science Council
その後、彼は全米科学会議の委員を務めた
Anxious person for medical students and chemists
医学生や化学者にとって気になる人
Served as the deputy director of the Biomedical Institute
生物医学研究所副所長を歴任
is now part of our Basic Neuroscience Society
現在、基礎神経科学協会の一員となっています
secretary general
秘書長
Recently invited to register by our new asylum director
最近、新しい亡命所長から登録するよう招待されました
Because the director of the International Affairs Office of our school headquarters
なぜなら、当校本部国際室長は、
So he's doing a lot of service work
それで彼はたくさんの奉仕活動をしています
He is going to tell us a very interesting topic today
今日彼は私たちにとても興味深い話題を話す予定です
Let’s talk about our miracle doctor system
ミラクルドクターシステムについて話しましょう
There is a very special cell
非常に特殊な細胞がある
I asked him to introduce his
私は彼に彼の紹介を依頼しました
please welcome
ようこそ
Goodnight everybody
おやすみ皆さん
I want to thank you all
皆さんに感謝したいです
Although there is a live broadcast, you are still here
生放送なのに君はここにいる
so i thank you very much
だからとても感謝しています
Today I would first like to thank our grandson Mi for introducing me
今日はまず、私を紹介してくれた孫のミーに感謝したいと思います。
He not only introduced me on behalf of the vice president
彼は副大統領に代わって私を紹介してくれただけではありません
and probably many of you here know
そしておそらくここにいる皆さんの多くは知っているでしょう
He is also a neuroscience researcher
彼は神経科学の研究者でもあります
So today if we have any questions
それでは今日、何かご質問がございましたら
it's too difficult for us to discuss
私たちにとって議論するのは難しすぎる
I want to ask my grandson Mi to leave the hospital
孫のミーちゃんに退院してもらいたい
I would also like to thank our colleagues in Academia Sinica
中央研究院の同僚にも感謝したいと思います。
Assisted me in many preparations
色々な準備を手伝ってくれました
very happy
とても幸せです
What's super interesting today is
今日の超興味深いことは、
Some people from my lab also came
私の研究室からも何人か来てくれました
I want to talk about them on this point
この点について話したいと思います
is our lab where we do this type of research
私たちの研究室はこの種の研究を行っています
Not just a teacher
ただの教師ではない
we need some young scholars
若い学者が何人か必要です
work hard with us
私たちと一緒に頑張ってください
So what I'm talking about today
それで今日私が話していることは
wait a minute there will be an online
ちょっと待ってください、オンラインになります
I have a summary to share with you
皆さんと共有したい要約があります
I should also mention that
それについても言及しておきます
Today's prepared materials
本日用意した材料
I try to translate most of it into Chinese
ほとんどを中国語に翻訳してみます
because we cherish the opportunity
私たちはこの機会を大切にしているので
We can share our
私たちは共有できます
How we think about something and how we do it
私たちが何かをどのように考え、どのように実行するか
that also needs everyone
それもみんなが必要だ
Just give us some of your opinions and suggestions
ご意見やご提案をお聞かせください
How many new slides are there?
新しいスライドは何枚ありますか?
What's new is the slideshow.
新しいのはスライドショーです。
Because of the relationship of time it is very close
時間の関係でとても近いです
so it's basically in english
なので基本的には英語です
But it's not for you, it's for me
でもそれはあなたのためではなく、私のためです
it's my super
それは私のスーパーです
So please include
それで、含めてください
Okay, before I start, I would like to thank the artist from the Biomedical Institute of our Academia Sinica
さて、始める前に、中央研究院生物医学研究所のアーティストに感謝したいと思います。
Many of our referrals today are handled with their assistance
現在、私たちの紹介の多くは彼らの支援を受けて処理されています
Basically, Academia Sinica is a place that attaches great importance to cooperation
中央研究院は基本的に連携を重視するところです
We need everyone's joint efforts in many things
多くのことにおいてみんなの協力が必要です
You should have read this matter many times in the newspapers, right?
この件は新聞で何度も読んだはずですよね？
We are now an aging society
今、私たちは高齢化社会を迎えています
In an aging society
高齢化社会の中で
That's the next year
それは翌年です
At that time, 14% of our compatriots over the age of 65
当時、65歳以上の同胞の14％は
Well, wait until the year I retire
まあ、退職する年まで待ってください
we will have
私たちは持っています
We are a super-aged society
超高齢社会を迎えます
This is 20% 20% 20% 20%
これは 20% 20% 20% 20% です
So everyone can understand why we are in the newspaper
私たちが新聞に載っている理由を誰もが理解できるように
often see long photos
長い写真をよく見る
often see how to take care of our family
私たちの家族の世話をする方法をよく見ます
this is because
それの訳は
The elderly population will have multiple chronic diseases
高齢者は複数の慢性疾患を抱えることになる
Here is an interesting article from the Legislative Yuan
立法院の興味深い記事はこちら
This is what I wanted to say when I watched it four years ago
4年前に観た時に言いたかったのはこれだ
wow the legislature is really good to us
うわー、議会は本当に私たちに良くしてくれます
because they wrote a
彼らはこう書いたから
That is, they wrote an article saying
それが彼らが書いたことです
take a look at
を見てみましょう
This article is from the 101st year of the Republic of China
この記事は中華民国101年のものです。
They announced it four years ago
彼らは4年前にそれを発表した
say 40 years later
40年後に言う
That is, 30 years from now
つまり30年後
The number of people with dementia will exceed 720,000
認知症患者は72万人を超える
After that, it was more serious
その後はさらに大変なことになりました
because everyone has a family
誰にも家族がいるから
So it affects our population of 23 million
つまり、2,300万人の人口に影響を与えるのです
inside it may affect
内部に影響を与える可能性があります
maybe a quarter to a fifth
おそらく4分の1から5分の1
this is very very serious
これはとてもとても深刻です
So what about our Legislative Yuan?
それでは、我が国の立法院はどうなるのでしょうか？
They instruct the Executive Yuan
彼らは行政院に指示する
what are you doing
あなたは何をしている
They said that the Executive Yuan should instruct the National Science Council
彼らは行政院が国家学術会議に指示すべきだと主張した。
as now
今のように
The Ministry of Science and Technology also cooperates with Academia Sinica to develop
科学技術省も中央研究院と協力して開発しています。
Antibodies and Drugs for Improving Institutional Syndrome
施設内症候群を改善するための抗体と薬剤
four years ago they said so
4年前、彼らはそう言った
Many of our colleagues work hard to do this
私たちの同僚の多くはこれを実現するために一生懸命働いています
in various fields
さまざまな分野で
But these four years
でもこの4年間
it's not an easy thing
それは簡単なことではありません
the whole world is like this
世界全体がこんな感じだ
I'll share it with you later
後で共有します
Our observations on these things
これらに関する私たちの観察
I should mention it first
最初に言及しておきます
what if in this situation
この状況だったらどうなるか
We also saw in the report
レポートでも拝見しましたが
Some of our long-term care facilities will start to emerge
長期介護施設がいくつか誕生し始める
Our Ministry of Science and Technology also led some
私たちの科学技術省もいくつかの取り組みを主導しました。
Brain science-based research projects
脳科学に基づく研究プロジェクト
So actually we all work very hard
だから実際、私たちは皆とても一生懸命働いています
The whole world is working hard
世界中が頑張ってるよ
This one is my little tide
これは私の小さな潮です
when did this happen
いつこんなことが起こったのか
happened last week
先週起こった
what's the matter
どうしたの
There is a biotech company in the United States
アメリカにバイオテクノロジー企業がある
he has an antibody
彼は抗体を持っています
This antibody does a lot of things
この抗体は多くの働きをします
How long? 27 years
どのくらいですか? 27 年
This antibody is curative
この抗体は治療効果があります
What about the usage of this antibody?
この抗体の用途についてはどうですか？
every month you go to the hospital
あなたは毎月病院に行きます
and you let it into your blood
そしてあなたはそれをあなたの血中に入れます
once
一次
Then everyone thinks it might cure the cure
そうすれば誰もがそれが治療法を治してくれるかもしれないと考える
Didn't expect it to be last week
先週だとは思わなかった
It proves that it cannot support
サポートできないことを証明する
Can't heal the disease?
病気は治らないの？
able to slow down
ゆっくりできる
so you can predict what will happen
それで何が起こるかを予測できる
what happened
どうしたの
Everyone is very sad
みんなとても悲しいです
Especially some professors of the Cultivation Society
特に栽培協会の一部の教授たちは
because they are full of expectations
彼らは期待でいっぱいだから
Think about it in 27 years
27年後に考えてみよう
Another thing is the stock market crash
もう一つは株式市場の暴落です
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
The company's stock fell 10%
その会社の株は10%下落した
also cut flowers
切り花も
Other stocks also adjusted on that day
この日は他の銘柄も調整
So express how disappointed everyone is
だからみんながどれほどがっかりしているかを表現してください
that's it
それでおしまい
You see this topic is very interesting
このトピックはとても興味深いですね
it title it says
それはタイトルです
but oh
でもああ
The treatment of this substantial disease is still in progress
この重大な病気の治療はまだ進行中です
That is to say, everyone did not give up their efforts.
つまり、誰もが努力を諦めなかったのです。
But he is really difficult
でも彼は本当に難しい人だよ
This person is also famous
この人も有名です
This man's name is Daley Baltimore
この男の名前はデイリー・ボルティモアです
He once won the Nobel Prize in 1975
彼は1975年にノーベル賞を受賞した
He was only 38 years old
彼はまだ38歳だった
he is very very powerful
彼はとてもとてもパワフルです
Served as president of several American universities
アメリカのいくつかの大学の学長を歴任
He is almost like a Taiwanese theorist
彼はまるで台湾の理論家のようだ
He has contributed to the development of various important academic
彼はさまざまな重要な学術の発展に貢献してきました。
both make suggestions
どちらも提案をする
He wrote an article earlier this year
彼は今年初めに記事を書きました
because we all see
私たち全員が見ているから
studying neurological diseases
神経疾患の研究
How much effort is needed on this matter
この問題に関してどれだけの努力が必要か
Then I think many colleagues here
それから、ここには多くの同僚がいると思います
maybe less
多分少ないです
The United States has spent a lot of money in recent years
米国は近年多額の資金を費やした
to do research on the brain
脳の研究をする
So he stood up and spoke
それで彼は立ち上がって話しました
some very important words
いくつかの非常に重要な言葉
He said everyone felt
誰もが感じていると彼は言った
It seems that we should start doing applications or should start doing basics
応用を始めるべきか、基礎を始めるべきのようです
Maybe there are two ideas, right?
おそらく 2 つのアイデアがありますよね?
I should have reported to everyone first
先にみんなに報告すべきだった
The slice I prepared today
今日用意したスライス
The file is almost an hour
このファイルは約 1 時間です
But because of knowledge and thinking, the most important thing for us is to be able to share our ideas with you.
しかし、知識と思考力があるため、私たちにとって最も重要なことは、私たちのアイデアを皆さんと共有できることです。
There are all kinds of questions
あらゆる種類の質問があります
So you are welcome to interrupt me at any time and you can follow me
だから、いつでも私に割り込んでいただいて構いませんし、私をフォローしていただいても大丈夫です
we can discuss some issues you are welcome
いくつかの問題について話し合うことができます、歓迎します
We have discussed this concept
私たちはこの概念について議論しました
In the final analysis, should research be applied or basic?
最終的に、研究は応用的なものにするべきでしょうか、それとも基礎的なものにするべきなのでしょうか?
Then this old Qi, a very important scholar
それからこの古いチー、非常に重要な学者です
He is 79 years old this year
彼は今年79歳になる
Everyone knows I don't know everyone here
誰もが知っています、私はここにいる全員を知りません
Do you think your chances of getting Shi Zhi's disease are high?
あなたが石芝病にかかる可能性は高いと思いますか?
So everyone is a confident person
だからみんな自信家なんです
Why? If you live to be over 85
なぜでしょうか?85歳以上まで生きるなら
chance is half
確率は半分です
So in other words, only compatriots with very long lives have the chance
つまり、非常に長生きした同胞だけがそのチャンスを持っているということだ
usually
いつもの
so
それで
then we also hope
それなら私たちも願っています
if everyone works hard
みんなが頑張れば
maybe by the time you're 85
たぶん85歳までには
maybe we've found a way
たぶん私たちは方法を見つけた
This is of course the goal
もちろんこれが目標です
yes
はい
at last
最後
Finally one of my slices is working together
ついにスライスの 1 つが連携するようになりました
All right
わかった
Let's talk about this at the end
これについては最後に話しましょう
this important scholar
この重要な学者
He said
彼は言った
why do we have so much difficulty
なぜ私たちはこんなにも困難を抱えているのでしょうか
because
なぜなら
We don't know enough about the basics
私たちは基本的なことを十分に理解していません
What we know about the nervous system
神経系について私たちが知っていること
understanding of nerve cells
神経細胞の理解
need to go further
さらに進む必要がある
Then my grandson didn't mention it just now
すると孫は今そのことについては言いませんでした
I have been in the past ten years
私は過去10年間に
took some effort to make medicine
薬を作るのに少し苦労した
I must reflect very sincerely
真摯に反省しなければなりません
I think
私が思うに
we often
私たちはよく
Dilemmas in Drug Development
医薬品開発におけるジレンマ
because we don't know enough about biology
私たちは生物学について十分な知識がないからです
so here
それでここで
our great
私たちの偉大な
this very important scholar
この非常に重要な学者
He made a point that I admire
彼は私が賞賛する点を指摘した
He said
彼は言った
Did you say how to work hard?
頑張り方って言いましたか？
I think his suggestions can be very useful for your reference.
彼の提案はあなたの参考として非常に役立つと思います。
This is the suggestion of scholars
これは学者の提案です
but wait a minute some are
でもちょっと待ってください。
It may have something to do with us personally
この比較は私たち個人に関係があるかもしれません
we'll come back to this part
この部分に戻ります
this he mentioned
彼はこれについて言及しました
All scholars must keep their eyes open
すべての学者は常に目を開いていなければなりません
Talk to you about people from different fields
さまざまな分野の人々について話しましょう
Let's see if there is any new technological development
新しい技術開発があるかどうか見てみましょう
Because why do we have so much trouble
だって、なぜ私たちはこんなにも問題を抱えているのでしょう
It's because the technology may not be there yet
テクノロジーがまだ存在していない可能性があるため、
So the first one he thought said
そこで彼が最初に考えたのはこう言った
Should be very active technological development
技術開発が非常に活発になるはずです
new technology
新技術
The second point he said that our data should be shared
彼が言った 2 番目の点は、私たちのデータは共有されるべきだということです。
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
i know i'm gonna tell you
私はあなたに言うつもりだと知っています
you have to tell me
あなたは私に言わなければなりません
We can reduce a lot of problems
多くの問題を減らすことができます
when knowledge is shared
知識が共有されるとき
Is there any way to make it more efficient
もっと効率化する方法はありますか
then easier
そうすればもっと簡単です
So it's not just us who do neuroscience
つまり、神経科学を行っているのは私たちだけではありません
In fact, people in the technology industry and people in the information industry
実際、テクノロジー業界の人も情報業界の人も、
these friends
この友達たち
should all come in together
全員が一緒に入るべきです
again that is to say
またまた、つまり
Basic science is very, very important
基礎科学はとてもとても重要です
we must know more
私たちはもっと知らなければなりません
Of course, he also talked about it in this
もちろんこの記事でも語っています
Of course clinical trials should be better designed
もちろん臨床試験はより適切に設計されるべきである
Then what
じゃあ何
Maybe we have to take a long look at the above and work hard
おそらく私たちは上記のことをよく見て、一生懸命働く必要があるでしょう
and develop new drugs
そして新薬を開発する
so this is his personal opinion
これは彼の個人的な意見です
But it is important that he mentioned
しかし、彼が言及したことは重要です
He said it takes effort
彼は努力が必要だと言いました
It's everyone working together
みんなで力を合わせて頑張っています
But his starting point must be basic research
しかし彼の出発点は基礎研究に違いない
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
I don't know if everyone will sit
全員座れるか分からない
in your seat
あなたの席で
you're actually a little disappointed
あなたは実際には少しがっかりしています
because you wish
あなたが望むから
there is a medicine soon
もうすぐ薬があります
then
それから
well like this
まあこのように
that's what I wish I was
それが私がそうであってほしいと願うものです
By the age of 85
85歳までに
there are already such drugs
すでにそのような薬はあります
Then of course we are working hard in this direction
もちろん、私たちはこの方向に一生懸命取り組んでいます
But we still have to tell you
しかし、私たちはまだあなたに伝えなければなりません
He still needs basic research
彼にはまだ基礎研究が必要です
Further research
さらなる研究
then we will work together
それなら一緒に働きましょう
The reason for this is actually just to mention that
この理由は実際に言及するだけです。
we need to know more
私たちはもっと知る必要があります
If we have some young classmates here
ここに若いクラスメイトがいたら
young researcher
若手研究者
no matter what field you are in
どの分野にいても
we all need you
私たち全員があなたを必要としています
especially the nervous system of the brain
特に脳の神経系
And the thing about brain cells
そして脳細胞について
So today I want to share with you a few topics
そこで今日はいくつかのトピックを共有したいと思います
one is a brain cell
一つは脳細胞です
a nerve cell
神経細胞
Because this may be less heard by everyone in the past
なぜなら、これは以前はあまり聞かれなかったかもしれないからです
The last point is that I want to share with you
最後にお伝えしたいのは、
We are not just me in Academia Sinica
中央研究院にいるのは私だけではありません
And we have several related laboratories
関連する研究所もいくつかあります
How do we study related issues
関連する問題をどのように研究するか
some if too thin
薄すぎる場合は少し
We look at the relationship between time
時間と時間の関係を見てみましょう
probably won't go into details
おそらく詳細には触れないでしょう
I think this may have something to do with everyone's interest
おそらくこれは皆さんの興味と関係があると思います
So mainly these three parts
つまり主にこの 3 つの部分です
brain cells i believe in here
私はここを信じている脳細胞
Everyone will always come to listen to the knowledge test
みんないつも知識テストを聞きに来ます
must be very very normal
とてもとても普通のはずです
read for a long time
長い間読んだ
a person with a lot of books a person with a lot of interest
たくさんの本を持っている人 たくさんのことに興味がある人
So you should all know what a brain cell is
だから皆さんは脳細胞が何であるかを知っておくべきです
Everyone knows the brain. Someone knew it a long time ago.
脳については誰もが知っており、ずっと前から誰かが知っていました。
What is the front page and the back page of the brain responsible for?
脳のフロントページとバックページは何の役割を果たしていますか?
For example, the cerebellum is here. The cerebellum is responsible for the coordination of movements.
たとえば、ここに小脳がありますが、小脳は運動の調整を担当します。
Let's say our memory is the hippocampus, right?
私たちの記憶が海馬だとしましょう。
If we read a lot of popular science, we will see the hippocampus
一般的な科学をたくさん読めば、海馬がわかるでしょう
We know the hippocampus should be somewhere in the middle of this
海馬はこの真ん中のどこかにあるはずであることがわかっています
What about the hippocampus, if there is some protein in it
タンパク質が含まれている場合、海馬はどうでしょうか
If it accumulates abnormally, its function will become bad
異常に蓄積すると機能が悪くなる
So this is common knowledge
だからこれは常識です
I also want to remind you that it is in my information this time.
今回も私の情報にあることを思い出していただきたいと思います。
I put my relevant acknowledgments and references here
関連する謝辞と参考文献をここに記載します
In fact, there is a lot of useful information on the Internet
実はインターネット上には有益な情報がたくさんあります
But if you are interested, you can look further
しかし、興味がある場合は、さらに詳しく見てみることができます
We are in a very good time right now
私たちは今とても良い時期にいます
Why? Because the whole world is working on this part.
なぜかというと、世界中がこの部分に取り組んでいるからです。
Almost never in human history
人類の歴史上ほとんどない
What is known about the nervous system so far
神経系についてこれまでにわかっていること
For example, we see that this is a
たとえば、これは
Brain look
脳の外観
But in fact, the connection and network we just talked about
しかし実際には、先ほど話した接続とネットワークは、
Already have good
すでに良いものを持っています
sorry
ごめん
Many people are already doing it
すでに多くの人がやっている
So from one area of ​​the brain to the next
つまり、脳のある領域から次の領域へ
In fact, many people are studying
実際に勉強している人もたくさんいます
those studies
それらの研究
research?
リサーチ？
it basically gets thinner
基本的に薄くなります
For example, to tell you
たとえば、あなたに伝えるために
There's a place that might be about fear
恐怖についての場所があるかもしれない
then can you
それならできますか
something bad happened to you
あなたに何か悪いことが起こりました
take a medicine quickly
あなたはすぐに薬を飲みます
Inhibit the cranial nerves in that place
その場所の脳神経を抑制する
then you don't remember the bad things
そうすれば嫌なことは覚えていない
That's not bad, isn't it?
それは悪くないですよね？
It's a post-traumatic memory
それはトラウマ後の記憶です
So someone is actually thinking about this
誰かが実際にこれについて考えている
then i used to be
それから私はかつてそうでした
In a seminar abroad, I saw someone researching
海外のセミナーで研究している人を見ました
Where is the brain area of ​​successful people?
成功者の脳領域はどこにあるのでしょうか？
They can decide that two mice collide
彼らは2匹のネズミが衝突したと判断できる
Then what
じゃあ何
successful rats will squeeze you out
成功したネズミはあなたを締め出すでしょう
Then if it finds this area
このエリアを見つけたら
It uses electromagnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic magnetic
それは、電磁気を使用します 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気 磁気磁気
stimulate the area
その領域を刺激する
Originally a very playful mouse
もともととても遊び心のあるネズミ
will push you out now
今すぐあなたを押し出すでしょう
So the study of brain regions will provide us with a lot of insight into the nervous system
したがって、脳の領域を研究することで、神経系について多くの洞察が得られるでしょう。
this is scary
これは怖いです
You will want to say that when my son takes the exam
息子が受験したらそう言いたくなるだろう
I told him to get stimulated
私は彼に刺激を与えるように言いました
He might become very aggressive
彼は非常に攻撃的になるかもしれない
But there are many ethical norms in scientific research
しかし、科学研究には多くの倫理規範があります
So the more you know
だから知れば知るほど
It is likely that our specification will become clearer in the future
今後、仕様がより明確になる可能性があります
Brain Cells
脳細胞
I would like to introduce to you how many types of brain cells there are
脳細胞には何種類あるのかを紹介したいと思います。
Then what
じゃあ何
let's look at one
一つ見てみましょう
Interrelation diagram between them
それらの相関図
You may be able to understand these things more clearly
これらのことをより明確に理解できるかもしれません
what is the relative relationship
相対的な関係は何ですか
Everyone knows that nerve cells are the most important, right?
神経細胞が最も重要であることは誰もが知っていますよね?
It connects one area to another
あるエリアと別のエリアを繋ぐ
Here when the nerves are active
ここで神経が活発になると、
There will be many potentials going through
たくさんの可能性が生まれるだろう
The faster you pass it on, the more effective it will be
早く伝えれば伝えるほど効果が高まります
But it can't be too fast, too fast will cause problems
でも速すぎてもダメ、速すぎると問題が起きるよ
That looks like a wire, right?
ワイヤーのように見えますよね？
You want this wire to pass well
このワイヤーをうまく通してほしい
Then there are many friends here who must be good at collecting wires or machines
それから、ここにはワイヤーや機械を集めるのが得意な友達がたくさんいます
You'll know what must be on the outside of this wire
このワイヤーの外側に何があるかわかるでしょう
It's safe to wrap it up, right?
包んでおけば安心ですよね？
So there is a wrapped thing that is
それで、包まれたものがあります。
Oligodendrocyte
希突起膠細胞
It's called Saltu Gelge cells and it's specially wrapped
Saltu Gelge Cellsと呼ばれるもので、特別に包装されています。
Each cell contains 50 nerve cells
各細胞には 50 個の神経細胞が含まれています
The purpose is to make it incompatible with each other
目的は相互に互換性を持たないようにすることです
Electric shock?
電気ショック？
it's just a short circuit thank you
ただのショートです、ありがとう
will not short circuit
ショートしません
everyone knows that
誰もがそれを知っています
have a serious illness
深刻な病気を患っている
Rozum's oil is not
ロズムのオイルはそうではありません
That is its water warp
それが水の歪みです
right
右
It's the water warping that's the problem
問題は水の歪みです
And when there is no such water warping
そして、そのような水の反りがないとき
It reduces the entire nerve conduction by 30 times
神経全体の伝導を30分の1に減少させます
so is very
とてもそうです
such a serious problem
そんな深刻な問題
What else? Glial cells
他に何? グリア細胞
What is this cell? This cell is super important
この細胞は何ですか? この細胞は超重要です
they are all brains
彼らは皆頭脳だ
you can look inside your head
自分の頭の中を覗くことができる
85% are these cells
85%はこれらの細胞です
glial cells
グリア細胞
Is it big enough, you can see its relative relationship
十分な大きさですか、相対的な関係がわかりますか
But if you look carefully
でもよく見てみると
you will find
見つけるだろう
It is afraid of medicinal essence, why?
薬用エッセンスが怖いのですが、なぜですか？
Because one of its feet is with the blue color of nerve cells
片方の足が神経細胞の青い色をしているから
What's attached to the other foot? The red one
もう片方の足には何が付いていますか? 赤い方です
Blood vessel
血管
So can anyone guess what it is used for?
それで、それが何に使われるか誰か推測できますか？
Right, nutrition, support, nerve cells
そう、栄養、サポート、神経細胞
so
それで
Who is the most important person in Academia Sinica?
中央研究院で最も重要な人物は誰ですか?
dean
院長
The most important thing about Academia Sinica is a group of
中央研究院で最も重要なことは、
one horde one horde
一大群一大群
Researchers
研究者
support us dean
私たちをサポートしてください
glial cells
グリア細胞
Cells are our basic researchers
細胞は私たちの基礎研究者です
It's them
それは彼らです
they do a lot of work
彼らはたくさんの仕事をします
In a moment I will give you two
すぐに 2 つあげます
Blood vessels are of course important
血管ももちろん大切です
There is still one
まだ1つあります
Just keep looking over here
ただここを見続けてください
You see it's actually on the blood vessel
実際に血管の上にあることがわかります
it covers the blood vessels
それは血管を覆います
It also coats nerve cells
神経細胞もコーティングします
the blue part
青い部分
ok
Ok
now everyone starts to see
今では誰もが見始めています
Microfocus cells
微焦細胞
this cell is small
この細胞は小さいです
About 5-10% of this
このうち5～10％くらい
when is it serious
いつ深刻ですか
when the brain starts
脳が動き始めるとき
infected
感染した
less common
不太常見
degenerate
退化する
I don't know if you have elders
先輩がいるかどうかは知りませんが、
at home
自宅で
that is
あれは
Originally good minded and close to the people
もともと頭が良くて人懐っこい
everything is very good
すべてがとても良いです
fell down one day
ある日倒れた
or one day
またはある日
caught a cold
風邪を引いた
in and out of the hospital
病院の内外で
Sanity also begins to degenerate
正気も退化し始める
Then it got serious
それからそれは深刻になりました
This is what we call an immune response
これが免疫反応と呼ばれるものです
is very very serious
とてもとても深刻です
so this is
それでこれは
Microfocus cells
微焦細胞
caused by vitreous cells
硝子体細胞が原因で起こる
Our Academia Sinica also has some research colleagues
私たちの中央研究院にも研究仲間がいます
It's for vascular cells and immune response
血管細胞と免疫反応のためのものです
If you are interested in the future
将来に興味があるなら
You can respond to our Academia Sinica
中央研究院にご回答いただけます
they can be invited to speak
彼らは講演に招待されることができます
Many drugs are now
今では多くの薬が
for vascular cells
血管細胞用
Then after I finish speaking
それから、私が話し終えた後、
please remember the color
色を覚えておいてください
Let's start by showing a section of their specific appearance
まずはその具体的な姿の一部をお見せしましょう
Okay, it's also a cartoon picture
はい、これも漫画の絵です
But you can see how they relate to each other
しかし、それらが互いにどのように関係しているかがわかります
what is the relationship
関係は何ですか
This is the nerve cell we see
これが私たちが見ている神経細胞です
many nerve cells
多くの神経細胞
they are connected in a string
それらは文字列で接続されています
usually a whole string
通常は文字列全体
Then here comes ours
それから、こちらが私たちのものです
covered with wires
ワイヤーで覆われている
The outside is wrapped
外側は包まれています
Advantageous power pole blockage
有利過電柱塞
It protects the conduction of nerve cells
神経細胞の伝導を保護します
It is effective
効果的です
You can see that they are
であることがわかります。
parts of these conduction potentials very closely
これらの伝導電位の一部が非常に近くにある
all covered
すべてカバーされています
So in many neurodegenerations
したがって、多くの神経変性では
This section will see
このセクションでは、
It can be serious if its volume is reduced
量が減ると深刻な事態になる可能性があります
The appearance of white is our protagonist today to encircle and suppress cells
細胞を取り囲み抑制する白の出現が今日の主役です
part of it is on the nerve
その一部が神経にかかっている
You can see that it's wrapped around the nerves
神経に絡みついているのがわかります
it also links part of
の一部ともリンクしています
what we just talked about
私たちが今話したこと
Oligodendrocyl
オリゴデンドロシル
it's a lot
それは多い
We just said that there are 80
先ほど80人と言いましたが、
80 to 85 scale
80～85スケール
blood vessels appear
血管が現れる
Blood vessels are in this combination
血管はこの組み合わせです
So there is an angle that is
したがって、次のような角度があります
glial cells
グリア細胞
There is a horn that rests on the blood vessel
血管の上に角がある
The other corner is connected to the top of the nerve cell
もう一方の角は神経細胞の上部に接続されています
that form a very, very close one
それは非常に非常に近いものを形成します
In short
要するに
Normally, if nothing happens, these glial cells
通常、何も起こらなければ、これらのグリア細胞は
will form a structure in the brain
脳内に構造が形成されます
So your brain is very stable
つまりあなたの脳は非常に安定しているのです
is very safe
とても安全です
At the same time, there are some perigelatin cells shuttling inside
同時に、いくつかのペリゼラチン細胞が内部を往復しています。
They're kind of like cops inside their heads.
彼らは頭の中が警察官のようなものです。
When something is wrong, he will show up to solve some problems
何か問題があると、彼は問題を解決するために現れます
they are small
彼らは小さい
But when he sees something wrong, he will put
しかし、何かが間違っていることに気づいたとき、彼はこう言います。
he swallows or breaks him down
彼は彼を飲み込むか、壊してしまう
His role is mainly
彼の役割は主に、
It's just a group of cells
それはただの細胞の集まりです
functional neurons
機能性ニューロン
but we are sitting here now
でも私たちは今ここに座っています
The inner cortex of our brain
私たちの脳の内皮質
For example, we have a lot of neurons
たとえば、私たちにはたくさんのニューロンがあります
Then what
じゃあ何
Have you ever thought about
考えたことはありますか
He still wants some fluid to flow through, doesn't he?
彼はまだ液体が流れてほしいと思っていますよね？
Our nerve cells are like us
私たちの神経細胞は私たちと同じです
we want to eat we want to drink what more do we need
食べたい、飲みたい、これ以上何が必要ですか
We have to wait, so we must use the bathroom
待たなければならないのでトイレに行かなければなりません
So there are some topics here that are specifically
ここでは、特に次のようなトピックがいくつかあります。
Circulation Brain fluid is dedicated to circulation
循環 脳液は循環専用です
in this part and then do some communication
この部分でコミュニケーションを行ってください
Wait a minute, let's talk about sleep.
ちょっと待って、睡眠について話しましょう。
is related
関連している
So in the brain what we see
つまり、脳の中で私たちが見ているものは
you often you may see
よく見かけるかもしれません
There are layers of brains in popular science, right?
ポピュラーサイエンスには何層もの頭脳がありますよね？
Its real structure is like this
実際の構造はこんな感じです
built up in groups
グループで構築される
So just now I would like to introduce to you very simply
そこで今回はとても簡単にご紹介したいと思います
brain nerve cells
脳神経細胞
Brain cells are not just nerves, there are many cells
脳細胞は神経だけではなく、たくさんの細胞が存在します
Most of the people
ほとんどの人
If you could only study one type of cell in your life, what would you study?
人生で 1 種類の細胞しか研究できないとしたら、何を研究しますか?
nerve cells, right?
神経細胞ですよね？
it's the protagonist it's the protagonist
それは主人公です、それは主人公です
You want to be the main character, not the supporting role, right?
脇役ではなく主役になりたいですよね？
So in the past 20 years
それで、この20年間で
Most of the research is on nerve cells
研究のほとんどは神経細胞に関するものです
but it's been a long time
でも長い時間が経った
After a while we found
しばらくして私たちは見つけました
If neurons we don't know
ニューロンがわからない場合
also very serious
また非常に深刻な
So during the ten years
それで10年間の間に
There are a lot of researches on nerve cells
神経細胞に関する研究は数多くあります
Huh? Are the nerve cells in your brain healthy?
え? 脳の神経細胞は健康ですか?
OK, let's set up our own answers
OK、独自の答えを設定しましょう
like i'm over 50 years old
私は50歳を超えているような
so I'm often very worried about saying
だから言うのがとても心配になることが多いです
have i stepped into something like this
私はこのようなものに足を踏み入れたことがありますか
For example, if you start to forget things, you will be very nervous.
たとえば、物忘れをし始めると、とても不安になります。
Yes or no?
はい、もしくは、いいえ？
Neurocytes have two functions
神経細胞には2つの機能があります
Very important
とても重要
one is to provide energy
一つはエネルギーを供給すること
Healthy or not
健康かどうか
Don't we humans have a way of speaking?
私たち人間には話す方法がないのでしょうか？
What is a happy person?
幸せな人とは何ですか？
eat, sleep
食べる、寝る
What else is there to laugh about?
他に笑うことがあるでしょうか？
Huh? It looks like this
ん？こんな感じですね
So today we're going to talk about nerve cells
さて、今日は神経細胞についてお話します。
has two important functions
2つの重要な機能があります
under normal conditions
通常の状態では
There is a supply of energy
エネルギーの供給はある
The one I showed you just now
さっき見せたやつ
I don't know if everyone has no impression
何か印象に残ったかどうかは分かりませんが、
That was just taken out of the human brain
それは人間の脳から取り出したばかりです
human brain
人間の脳
The outer layer of red line is the blood vessel
赤い線の外層が血管です
In our body, 20% of our blood goes to the brain
私たちの体内では、血液の 20% が脳に送られます。
So the brain is very, very important
つまり脳はとてもとても重要なのです
Blood vessels are very important
血管はとても大切です
Then today because of time
それでは今日は時間の関係で
I choose to give you only a very simple conclusion on this point.
この点については、非常に単純な結論だけをお伝えしたいと思います。
Basically, there may be glucose in blood vessels, for example
基本的に、血管内にはブドウ糖が存在する可能性があります。たとえば、
Then it will mainly go to the nerve cells.
それから主に神経細胞に行きます。
But there's a neurofocus cell in the middle
しかし、中央には神経焦点細胞があります
Strangely, glucose is converted into lactic acid through neurofocus cells
グルコースが神経焦点細胞を介して乳酸に変換されるのは非常に奇妙です
Then it enters the nerve cells and turns into energy
そして神経細胞に入りエネルギーに変わります。
At this time, it supplies many functions in the nerve cells.
このとき、神経細胞に多くの機能を供給します。
I'm sorry, I don't know why I can't see the background in this picture
ごめんなさい、この写真では背景が見えないのでわかりません
But just take my word for it
でも私の言葉をそのまま信じてください
is that neurofocal cells provide a role for blood vessel
それは神経焦点細胞が血管に役割を提供しているということです
supply energy to nerves
神経にエネルギーを供給する
so his health is very important
だから彼の健康はとても重要です
Then there's one more thing, is it clean?
それからもう一つ、きれいですか？
this point is very important
この点は非常に重要です
I don't know if everyone slept well
みんなよく眠れたか分からない
uncertain
不確かな
Then when I prepare this speech
それから、このスピーチを準備するとき、
After I prepare myself
自分の準備を整えてから
I'm so scared
とても怖いです
because that day
あの日だから
I sleep on a horizontal board
水平な板の上で寝ます
i want to say
私は言いたい
so get to sleep
だから寝なさい
otherwise very serious
それ以外の場合は非常に深刻です
let me tell you why
理由を教えてください
You have to sleep when you are tired, right?
疲れたら寝ないといけないですよね？
what's the benefit of sleeping
寝ることのメリットは何ですか
this is
これは
This is what our ancestors suggested, isn't it?
これは私たちの先祖が示唆したことですよね。
What is a few meters and a few inches, right?
数メートルと数インチって何ですか？
I don't know if you guys ever tell your kids
皆さんが子供たちに伝えたことがあるかどうかはわかりませんが、
or told someone
または誰かに言った
Tell my kids to go to sleep
子供たちに寝るように言ってください
he ignores me
彼は私を無視します
how many inches
何インチですか
Because of physical strength and intelligence
体力も知力もあるから
It is very important to form a good neural network
良好なニューラルネットワークを形成することが非常に重要です
can form a good memory
良い思い出を作ることができます
everyone remember
誰もが覚えています
joint from one area
1つのエリアからのジョイント
This area is very important, isn't it?
この辺は非常に重要ですよね。
there will be good
良いことがあるだろう
When we just talked about neuroimmunity
ちょうど神経免疫について話したとき
have good immunity
免疫力が良い
so this is very important
これはとても重要です
May reduce oxidative stress in the brain
脳内の酸化ストレスを軽減する可能性があります
Also slows down metabolism
代謝も低下します
give you a better rest
より良い休息を与えてください
But what about me recently
でも最近の私はどうですか？
we all know this
私たちは皆これを知っています
why on earth
なぜ地球上で
When I was doing some research in the United States recently
最近アメリカでリサーチをしていたとき
There is a study that I find particularly interesting
特に興味深いと思う研究があります
So I can share with you
だから私はあなたと分かち合うことができます
It is also an important function of nerve cells
神経細胞の重要な機能でもあります
this is a blood vessel
これは血管です
please imagine
想像してください
This is a nerve cell
これは神経細胞です
One foot binds nerves for energy
片足はエネルギーを得るために神経を束ねる
A foot encases blood vessels
足は血管を包み込んでいる
But what about the nerve cells and the blood vessels?
しかし、神経細胞や血管はどうなるのでしょうか？
It also has a very thin layer of liquid
非常に薄い液体の層もあります
a space of
のスペース
allow brain fluid to flow through
脳液が流れるようにする
do you remember
覚えていますか
I just said
私はちょうど言いました
group of nerves
神経のグループ
from the inside
中から
it has brain fluid
脳液がある
flow like this
このように流れます
Then when we thought about it, you said how we arrange it, we knew it.
それから私たちがそれについて考えたとき、あなたは私たちがそれをどのようにアレンジするかについて言いました、私たちはそれを知っていました。
How do nerve cells line up?
神経細胞はどのように並んでいるのですか？
Then our nerve cells breathe with glucose
そして私たちの神経細胞はブドウ糖で呼吸します
How does it metabolize? Does it also go to the toilet?
どのように代謝するのでしょうか?トイレにも行きますか?
It's just a little bit, and then it goes to the toilet, how does it clean up?
ちょっとだけでトイレに行ってしまうのですが、どうやって掃除しているのでしょうか？
So this part is actually very interesting
この部分は実際非常に興味深いです
Then there is a brain in the brain called brain muscle randomness
そして、脳には脳筋ランダム性と呼ばれる脳が存在します。
Have you ever heard of the keel water?
キールウォーターについて聞いたことがありますか？
Sometimes the doctor you go to the hospital may ask you
時々、病院に行く医師か​​ら尋ねられることがあります。
You don't want to smoke the keel water like this
こんな風にキールウォーターを吸いたくないでしょう
Because there are many problems in the brain
脳には色々な問題があるから
It will appear in the brain muscle randomly
脳筋にランダムで出現します
What is this? It's interesting.
これは何ですか? 面白いですね。
it's in the ventricles in the brain
それは脳の心室にあります
inside a brain outside
脳の中の外
In fact, you see, our creation of heaven and earth is very mysterious.
実際、私たちの天地創造は非常に神秘的です。
Our brains are encased in a layer of fluid, which is safe.
私たちの脳は液体の層に包まれており、安全です。
This fluid is brain muscle random
この液体は脳筋ランダムです
we make it from it has a ventricle
私たちは心室を持ってそれを作ります
There are some capillaries in the ventricle
心室にはいくつかの毛細血管があります
It's basically our blood that passes through this microvascular cluster
基本的に私たちの血液はこの微小血管群を通過します
kind of like a filter
フィルターのようなもの
So its composition is very similar to that of blood, except that it has very little protein
そのため、タンパク質が非常に少ないことを除けば、その組成は血液と非常に似ています。
what's the point here
ここで何の意味があるのですか
Have you ever thought about the question of queuing?
行列の問題について考えたことがありますか?
Now the problem with urination comes, that is, you have blood going in to provide you with nutrients
ここで、排尿の問題が発生します。つまり、栄養を供給するために血液が流入することになります。
It's when your, basically your nerve cells expel something bad
それは基本的に神経細胞が何か悪いものを追い出すときです
Then this bad thing is contained in the small
そうすれば、この悪いものは小さなものに含まれています
That bad protein that causes plaque
プラークの原因となる悪玉タンパク質
They are secreted by nerve cells
それらは神経細胞によって分泌されます
Now is a good time to clean up
今は掃除をするのに良い時期です
So how do we neuroscientists do things like this?
では、私たち神経科学者はどのようにしてこのようなことを行うのでしょうか?
This is also very interesting
これもとても興味深いですね
That's in the back of the head, that's the place
それは後頭部、そこです
they can be opened
それらは開けることができます
Punch in two different colors
2色のパンチ
Then, open the skull and put it inside
次に、頭蓋骨を開いて中に入れます
It's a microscope
それは顕微鏡です
Then the activity of the brain can be observed
そうすれば脳の活動が観察できる
what's important
何が重要ですか
it's funny to say
言うのは面白いです
it has two different colors
2つの異なる色があります
dye
染料
Let's take a look at this
これを見てみましょう
What about when the red dye is injected?
赤い染料を注入するとどうなるでしょうか？
what time awake
何時に起きていますか
right now we are here we are awake, right?
今、私たちはここにいて、目覚めていますよね？
That
それか
The dye is punched in from the back side
染料は裏側から打ち込まれます
after trying
試した後
Look every thirty minutes
30分ごとに見る
it's still here
それはまだここにあります
but if you fall asleep
でも眠ってしまったら
come and see
見に来て
It is not in the original place, it will run outside
本来の場所になくて外を走っている
so what does this mean
それで、これはどういう意味ですか
Asleep yes thanks
眠っています、はい、ありがとう
while asleep
眠っている間
all of this
これすべて
The time and order of this arrangement will be much faster
この手配の時間と順序ははるかに速くなります
so
それで
Such a study is
そのような研究は、
represents many meanings
多くの意味を表します
So they have a concept that is a garbage truck for the brain
彼らは脳のゴミ収集車という概念を持っています
The concept is that
コンセプトは、
Basically in the brain there are also arteries and veins
基本的に脳には動脈と静脈もあります
There's a lot of nerve cells in the middle, and we just saw the nerve worm
真ん中にはたくさんの神経細胞があり、ちょうど神経虫が見えました
Nerve cells expel something bad
神経細胞は悪いものを排出する
When does our brain fluid exchange with hydrocephalus fluid and brain fluid?
私たちの脳液は、いつ水頭症液や脳液と交換されるのでしょうか？
The amazing thing is that he is exchanging with the small air between the nerve cells and the blood vessels.
すごいのは、神経細胞と血管の間の小さな空気とやりとりしていることです。
what happens when you sleep
寝たら何が起こるか
The nerve cell becomes smaller
神経細胞が小さくなる
bigger space
より大きなスペース
So we used the idea of ​​the underground sewer to think if he could get through soon
そこで私たちは地下下水道のアイデアを使って考えます、それはすぐに通過するでしょうか？
So this is the result of their research
これが彼らの研究結果です
We can come to the Colossus to fantasize, shall we?
巨像に来て空想してみませんか？
That's what they did later, this team
それが彼らが後でやったことだよ、このチームは
they made a funny one
彼らは面白いものを作りました
Look at the green ones are nerve cells
見てください、緑色のものは神経細胞です
so you pretend you're neurons
だから君は自分がニューロンであるふりをする
Inside a cell, you can see
細胞の中を見ると、
Red, of course, this is a blood vessel
赤、もちろんこれは血管です
This is a glial cell
これはグリア細胞です
you look inside
あなたは中を見ます
There's a small gap here
ここに小さな隙間があります
This is the space that the brain and machine pass through at will.
ここは脳と機械が自由に通過する空間です。
It also exchanges with the brain fluid outside
外部の脳液とも交換します
These are the things that make our brains
これらは私たちの脳を作るものです
Sick of these fat intestines
この太った腸にはうんざりだ
or some small, bad protein
または、小さくて悪いタンパク質
it goes through, it's a vein
それは通過します、それは静脈です
it will exchange with this side
こちら側と交換します
and then after flowing out
そして流れ出た後
to our lymphatics
私たちのリンパ管に
Lymphatic vessels will come out
リンパ管が出てきます
Then it goes to the liver to the kidneys
それから肝臓、腎臓に行きます
will be hydrolyzed
加水分解されてしまいます
so sleep well
だからよく寝てください
I saw this and immediately went back to sleep
これ見てすぐ寝た
really, it's important
本当に、それは重要です
I have another one, this video is for everyone to watch
もう一つあります、このビデオは誰でも見ることができます
this is sad for me
これは私にとって悲しいことです
I feel sad
悲しいな
This mouse is two to three months old
このマウスは生後2〜3か月です
And then around eight to...
それから8時くらいに...
12 year old boy
12歳の男の子
Are they the same?
彼らは同じですか？
That's where they punch in the dye
そこに染料を打ち込むのです
then 30 minutes later
それから30分後
individual brain slices
個々の脳のスライス
see where it is distributed
どこで配布されているか見てみる
And what?
そして何？
its small
それは小さい
It's the small molecules that move very fast.
非常に速く動くのは小さな分子です。
it's red
赤です
The bigger molecules run slower
分子が大きいほど速度が遅くなる
it is green
それは緑色です
if you see red and yellow
赤と黄色が見えたら
red and green
赤と緑
overlap means it runs as fast
オーバーラップは同じ速度で実行されることを意味します
why
なぜ
These cells are relatively small
これらの細胞は比較的小さいです
Then there is more space
そしたらもっとスペースあるよ
It runs all the way regardless of size
サイズに関係なく最後まで走ります
i just told you
私はちょうどあなたに言いました
my secret how old am i
私の秘密 私は何歳ですか
let's see this
これを見てみましょう
what about the mouse
マウスはどうですか
is 18 months
18ヶ月です
almost equal to 72 years old
72歳にほぼ等しい
grandpa or grandma like this
おじいちゃんやおばあちゃんはこんな感じ
You see it's all the same experiment
全部同じ実験だということがわかりますね
Did you see how it ran?
どうやって動いたか見ましたか？
just didn't run
ただ走らなかっただけ
in this way
この上
So age makes a difference
だから年齢が違いを生むんだよ
that also explains
それも説明します
Why in neurodegenerative diseases
なぜ神経変性疾患で
often happens
よく起こります
at an older age
高齢になって
But then I also encouraged myself
でも、私も自分を励ましました
I now also encourage everyone
私も今、みんなを励ましています
That is to say age is not real age
つまり年齢は実年齢ではない
age is how we take care of ourselves
年齢は私たちが自分自身を大切にする方法です
then we have to exercise
それなら運動しなければなりません
Really, you trust me to exercise
本当に、あなたは私が運動することを信頼しています
It has a very important impact on nerve peroneal compression disease
腓骨神経圧迫疾患に非常に重要な影響を及ぼします
If there is a chance, I will tell you later
機会があればまたお知らせしますね
Evidence from our experiment
私たちの実験から得られた証拠
Extremely important impact you exercise sleep well
運動と睡眠の質に非常に重要な影響を与える
don't be too lucky
不要太優緣
Usually your cranial nerves are more
通常、脳神経はもっと
The system will
システムは、
It just ages slower
ただ老化が遅くなるだけです
condition will be better
状態は良くなります
but what's the point here
しかし、ここで何の意味があるのですか
that is
あれは
there is really a difference in age
本当に年齢差があります
Is it good or not? It really makes a difference.
それが良いかどうか、それは本当に大きな違いを生みます。
so here
それでここで
It's just emphasizing on getting a good night's sleep, okay?
良質な睡眠をとることを強調しているだけですよね？
then we
それから私たち
just talking
ただ話しているだけ
glial cells for
グリア細胞
Sufficient energy and cleanliness
十分なエネルギーと清潔さ
has great importance
非常に重要です
Do you have some neurological diseases?
何か神経​​系の病気があるのでしょうか？
We now know from the literature
私たちは今、文献から知っています
because of his glial cells
彼のグリア細胞のせいで
His following traits change
彼の次の特性が変化する
overactive his nervous system
彼の神経系が過剰に活動している
Instead, many degenerative diseases
その代わり、多くの変性疾患が
So let's talk about degradation
それでは劣化について話しましょう
Nakahara-in
中原院
I want to talk to you very soon
すぐに話したいです
We are in Zhongyuanyuan
私たちは中原園にいます
what we do with people
私たちは部分的に人々と協力してどのような仕事をしていますか
So using mouse models of disease to study neurodegenerative diseases
そこで、マウス疾患モデルを使用して神経変性疾患を研究する
Do you accept disease mice for research?
研究用に病気のマウスを受け入れますか?
May I
いいですか
When I first debuted
デビューしたての頃
I once heard a friend complain
友人の愚痴を聞いたことがある
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
He's basically a clinical worker
彼は基本的には臨床従事者です
He said you people are weird
彼はあなた達は変人だと言いました
You specialize in studies with flies and mice
あなたはハエとネズミを使った研究を専門としています
flies are fruit flies
ハエはショウジョウバエです
And then how to experiment with flies and mice
そして、ハエとネズミを使った実験方法
But basically we wait and see
でも基本的には様子見です
There are some specific reasons for this
これにはいくつかの具体的な理由があります
good
良い
neurodegeneration
神経変性
I still have to be very
私はまだとてもそうしなければなりません
that is
あれは
very heavy to say but so far
言うのは非常に重いですが、これまでのところ
There really is no drug available so far
実は今のところ治療薬はない
However, many drugs are already undergoing clinical trials
しかし、多くの薬はすでに臨床試験中です
In addition to the degeneration we just talked about
先ほど話した退化に加えて、
The basic antibody
基本的な抗体
In addition to no success, there is actually another antibody
成功しないだけでなく、実際には別の抗体が存在します
It was mentioned in the June issue of Nature this year
今年6月にNature誌に掲載されました
Their initial research looks pretty good
彼らの初期研究はかなり良いようです
So please don't be too heavy
だからあまり重くならないでください
But it's true that we're going to work together
でも、一緒にやっていくのは本当だ
Okay, let's just mention it
さて、それについて言及しましょう
These neurodegenerative diseases all have one thing in common
これらの神経変性疾患にはすべて共通点があります
This is a brain slice
これは脳のスライスです
that different disease
その違う病気
But we can all see that there are some proteins
しかし、タンパク質が存在することは誰でもわかります。
piled up in the middle
真ん中に積まれている
This is why I said earlier
これが先ほど言った理由です
to shoot
撮影する
So what do these diseases include?
では、これらの病気には何が含まれるのでしょうか?
including dementia
認知症も含めて
including some forms of dysmenorrhea
いくつかの形態の月経困難症を含む
including Huntington's disease
ハンチントン病を含む
Including ship moving
船の移動も含めて
Also includes cerebellar tail
小脳の尾引きも含む
Do you all remember this?
皆さんはこれを覚えていますか？
do you remember this movie
この映画を覚えていますか
Steel Alice
鋼鉄アリス
It's about a very smart scholar
とても賢い学者の話です
He later changed the course after the early onset dementia
彼はその後、若年性認知症を患い、進路を変更した。
Movies like this make us understand
このような映画は私たちに理解を与えてくれます
is when we meet ourselves or our loved ones
それは私たちが自分自身または私たちの愛する人に会ったときです
how to solve
の解き方
another famous movie
もう一つの有名な映画
do you remember
覚えていますか
take a landscape
風景を撮る
basically tailing off of the cerebellum
基本的には小脳尾
same question
同じ質問
different brain cells
さまざまな脳細胞
accumulation of different proteins
さまざまなタンパク質の蓄積
That
それか
Speaking of No Drugs Available
利用可能な薬がないと言えば
If you are a scholar of the Ministry of Science and Technology
科学技術省の学者の場合
Or the words of the head of the Ministry of Science and Technology
あるいは科学技術省長官の言葉
would you like to support
サポートしたいですか
There are 720,000 people with Shizhi disease, but we still need to support a rare disease with 2,000 people
Shizhi病患者は72万人いますが、それでも2,000人の希少疾患を支援する必要があります
let's talk
話しましょう
720,000 isn't it?
72万ですよね？
We worked so hard for that old man's money, right?
私たちはあのおじいさんのお金のために一生懸命働きましたよね？
It is true to say so, but it is too difficult for him
確かにそう言うけど、それは彼にとって難しすぎる
what is the reason
理由は何ですか
it's us sitting here
ここに座っているのは私たちです
I see everyone looks good
みんないい表情してるのが見える
but we all look different
でも私たちはみんな違うように見える
we eat different things
私たちは違うものを食べます
We have a slightly different genetic background
私たちはわずかに異なる遺伝的背景を持っています
cause if a disease
病気の場合の原因
not already genetic
すでに遺伝的ではない
know what words
何の言葉か知っていますか
too difficult
難しすぎる
too much money
お金が多すぎる
The 27 years of research just now
27年間の研究が今に至る
why so many people are sad
なぜ多くの人が悲しんでいるのか
he probably bought a lot of stocks
彼はおそらく株をたくさん買ったでしょう
he poured money in it
彼はそれにお金を注ぎました
anything a drug develops
薬が開発されるものなら何でも
Especially neuroleptics
特に神経弛緩薬
He must end up with thousands of studies
彼は最終的に何千もの研究をしなければならない
And a study takes three to five years
そして研究には3年から5年かかります
a lot of money in it
その中には大金が入っている
so this is difficult
だからこれは難しい
what can i do
私に何ができる
what can replace it
何がそれに代わるものか
The flies and mice we just talked about
先ほど話したハエとネズミについて
research model
研究モデル
What research models are available
どのような研究モデルが利用可能か
those research models
それらの研究モデル
if you want to use it
使いたいなら
The most effective is
最も効果的なのは、
Do you know what its genetic lesion is
その遺伝子病変が何であるか知っていますか
there is one more thing to say
もう一つ言うべきことがある
Do you know what a genetic disorder is
遺伝性疾患とは何か知っていますか
But do mice and people really want each other?
しかし、ネズミと人間は本当にお互いを求めているのでしょうか？
how are you going
調子はどうですか
my stomach doesn't want to
私の胃はそれを望んでいません
how do we go
どうやって行きますか
Decide that this model can be used
このモデルが使用可能であると判断する
what can be used
何が使えるのか
let's share
共有してみましょう
we are in this field
私たちはこの分野にいます
how do you do
ごきげんよう
Wu Yao's availability is as follows
ウー・ヤオの空き状況は以下の通りです
We do rare diseases
私たちは希少疾患を治療します
i have a very
私はとても持っています
my senior
私の先輩
Chen Yuanchong wishes that everyone may have heard of his name
チェン・ユアンチョンは誰もが自分の名前を聞いたことがあると願っています
He started with the treatment and drug development of rare diseases in China
彼は中国で希少疾患の治療と医薬品開発を始めました。
And then do it really, really well and be famous all over the world
そしてそれを本当に、本当にうまくやって、世界中で有名になるのです
He said something that I will always remember
彼は私がずっと覚えていることを言いました
He said we are a small country but we have a lot of love
彼は、私たちは小さな国だけど、たくさんの愛があると言いました
Why?
なぜ？
When we take money to prop up rare research
珍しい研究を支援するためにお金を取るとき
We are helping this group of people we are not helping him
私たちはこのグループの人々を助けていますが、彼を助けているわけではありません
who help him
彼を助ける人
But is a lot of help related to health insurance costs?
しかし、多くの援助は健康保険の費用に関連しているのでしょうか?
so a lot of money
とてもたくさんのお金
But now I want to make another point, which is that
しかし、ここで私は別の点を指摘したいと思います。
Although we are very loving
私たちはとても愛情深いのに、
maybe one thing is also important
もしかしたらもう一つ重要なこともあるかもしれない
This is a disease of 720,000 people, the big disease
これは72万人が罹患している大きな病気です
out of breath
息を切らして
So you can take a look. There are many big pharmaceutical companies abroad.
海外には大手製薬会社がたくさんあります。
They're all doing it for rare diseases
彼らは皆、希少疾患の治療に取り組んでいます
there are a few very specific reasons for that
それには非常に具体的な理由がいくつかあります
One is because their basic research is very good
一つは基礎研究が非常に優れているからです。
So there are good animal models
優れた動物モデルがあるということです
Many people study, because it is easier to study
勉強しやすいから勉強する人が多い
So you know what specific essence
つまり、具体的な本質が何であるかがわかります
where do you control it
どこでコントロールしますか
it's under your control, so you can research
それはあなたの管理下にあるので、あなたは研究することができます
But more important is the following
しかし、より重要なのは次のことです
How our medicines get into the brain
私たちの薬がどのように脳に入るのか
Have you ever thought that today there is a good medicine
今日は良い薬があると思ったことはありますか
how do you get in your head
どうやって頭に入ってくるの？
We just saw the blood vessels, right?
血管が見えただけですよね？
Blood vessels are a barrier, aren't they?
血管はバリアですよね。
How do you pass this barrier?
この障壁をどうやって乗り越えますか？
So in Taiwan, in the world
だから台湾でも世界でも
There are many studies on
については多くの研究があります
For example, with that nanoparticle
たとえば、そのナノ粒子では
How did you carry it over? Have you heard of it?
どうやってそれを引き継いだのですか? 聞いたことがありますか?
how to use ultrasound on the head
頭に超音波を使用する方法
had an ultrasound
超音波検査を受けた
Shake it, open your brain, let the barrier pass
振って、脳を開いて、バリアを通過させてください
Let the medicine go in, a lot of people are doing this
薬を入れてみましょう、多くの人がこれを行っています
so apart from
それとは別に
We are working on this rare time
私たちはこの珍しい時期に取り組んでいます
We will study how to enter the brain
脳に入る方法を研究します
Another important point is
もう一つ重要な点は、
Taking advantage of this opportunity, we also know
この機会を利用して、私たちも知っています
how to get rid of fast protein
高速プロテインを除去する方法
can we dissolve it soon
早く解散してもいいですか
can we get rid of it soon
すぐに取り除けますか
These are all brought out when researching the disease
そして、病気を研究するときにこれらすべてが明らかになります
what about here
ここはどうですか
to mention a
言及する
Huntington disease
ハンチントン病
Huntington's chorea
ハンチントン舞踏病
The cause of it is dyskinesia
原因はジスキネジア
dementia mental illness
認知症精神疾患
Mainly find a fine
主に罰金を見つける
That is, there are three GACs on it
つまり、3 つの GAC が存在します。
CAG repeat its repeat
CAGはその繰り返しを繰り返す
then everyone just say
そうしたらみんなが言うだけ
how much is this in taiwan
これは台湾でいくらですか
about two hundred to two thousand
約200から2000
very few
非常に少ない
then why
それでなんで
you will say strange
あなたは変なことを言うでしょう
How come you don't know how many
どうして何人か分からないのですか
Do you know why?
なぜなのかご存知ですか？
You have this disease, do you want others to know
あなたはこの病気にかかっています、他の人に知ってもらいたいですか
don't think so
そうは思わないでください
So it becomes difficult to investigate rare diseases
希少疾患の調査が難しくなる
but it's over the world
でもそれは世界中です
has a very important influence
非常に重要な影響力を持っています
Let me tell you about this professor
この教授についてお話しましょう
let's take a look
見てみましょう
wait a minute we watch the little mouse
ちょっと待って、小さなネズミを見てみましょう
The models we use to study drugs
薬の研究に使用するモデル
Does it really respond to a patient?
本当に患者に応えられるのか？
Don't start by introducing the Dr.
最初に医師を全員に紹介しないでください。
He and his wife have been separated for 40 years
彼と彼の妻は40年間別居している
10 years ago he knew he had Huntington disease
10年前、彼は自分がハンチントン病であることを知っていた
Then he did a lot of papers
それから彼はたくさんの書類を書きました
I also read his paper
私も彼の論文を読みました
Said they were doing schizophrenia
彼らは統合失調症をやっていると言った
think about a scholar
学者のことを考える
when he knew he had the disease
彼がその病気に罹っていると知ったとき
what will happen to him
彼に何が起こるでしょうか
he will be depressed
彼は落ち込んでしまうだろう
must be very very depressed
とてもとても落ち込んでいるに違いない
Because there is no medicine for this disease
この病気には特効薬がないので
But what?
でも何？
because he is a scholar
彼は学者だから
he knows what research is going on
彼はどのような研究が行われているかを知っています
he knows exercise is important
彼は運動が重要であることを知っています
So for 10 years
それで10年間
He washes five sesame eggs every day
彼は毎日ごま卵を5個洗います
The most important thing about this disease is movement disorder
この病気で最も重要なことは運動障害です
Let's see what the situation is like
どういう状況なのか見てみましょう
Wait a minute, let's see the little teacher
ちょっと待って、小さな先生に会いに行きましょう
The disease I want to mention is that it is a movement disorder
私が言及したい病気は運動障害であるということです
we can step back from here today
今日はここから退くことができる
i can come over
来てもいいよ
I'm very lucky
私はとても幸運です
Because the part of my brain that is responsible for the organization is very good
なぜなら、私の脳の組織を担当する部分は非常に優れているからです。
I can wave my hand today
今日は手を振ってもいいよ
It's because there is an organization called text
テキストという組織があるから
it's not easy to do
それは簡単ではありません
It is also emphasized here
ここでも強調されています
In fact, the exercise itself, hard work and perseverance are important
実際、運動自体、努力と忍耐力が重要です
But to say it again
でも、もう一度言うと
I just talked for a long time
つい長々と話してしまいました
you must want to say
きっと言いたいはずです
Wow, I talked for a long time about whether mice can be used
うわー、マウスが使えるかどうかについて長々と話しました
If mice were used for this experiment
この実験にマウスを使った場合
what are we looking at
私たちは何を見ているのですか
what to see
何を見てください
I developed it to you to dare to use it
あえてあなたに使ってもらうために開発しました
This is a big debate
これは大きな議論です
there is no standard answer
標準的な答えはありません
but let me tell you
でも言わせてください
How do we use this field
このフィールドをどのように使用するか
This is a special case
これは特殊なケースです
This mouse has a fragment installed on it, which is the patient's
このマウスには患者の断片が取り付けられています。
small gene fragment
小さな遺伝子断片
ok, then you can see it from the video
はい、それはビデオから見ることができます
Look at this mouse
このマウスを見てください
i don't know if you ever catch a mouse
あなたがネズミを捕まえたことがあるかどうかはわかりません
you mistook the mouse
マウスを間違えた
it is not happy so it will
それは幸せではないからそうなるだろう
The limbs move around randomly, it is to maintain balance
手足はランダムに動きますが、それはバランスを保つためです
This mouse has no way so when it degenerates
このマウスは退化するとどうしようもなくなる
it must be holding
それは持っているに違いない
So obviously it clings as it degenerates
明らかに、それは退化するにつれてくっついています
Then this mouse is sick
じゃあこのネズミは病気だ
Mouse will be a little lighter
マウスが少し軽くなる
Then let's see how to compare
それでは比較方法を見てみましょう
For example, life will be shortened, weight will be lost
例えば寿命が縮む、体重が減るなど
I have a friend who is
私には友人がいます。
Dr. Chen Zhongmin, Physician of Chang Gung Hospital
長庚病院医師、チェン・ジョンミン博士
He said he one day had a
彼はある日、
There is a pair, there is a mother with one
一対あり、一対を持つ母親もいる
Children in middle school come to see
中学生の子どもたちが見に来ます
He just told him this kid is weird
彼はこの子が変だと言ったばかりです
He's really miserable, assuming he won't
そうしないと仮定すると、彼は本当に惨めだ
not like this
こんなんじゃない
Just look at him as Honignton disease
彼をホニトン病として見てください
because he has lost weight
彼は体重が減ったので
Later it was discovered
その後発見されたのですが
His has that bad gene fragment
彼はその悪い遺伝子断片を持っています
that mouse
そのネズミ
And then there are plaques of this protein
そして、このタンパク質のプラークがあります
Decreased cognitive function Movement disorders
認知機能の低下 運動障害
So how do we create a mouse
では、どうやってマウスを作成するのか
Convince you that his research is valid
彼の研究が有効であることをあなたに納得させる
Here are a few examples, that is
以下にいくつかの例を示します。
we try to make it sound like
私たちはそれを次のように聞こえるように努めます
Then tell everyone, for example, the old tail said
それからみんなに言ってください、たとえば、古い尻尾は言いました
Then people can do resonance verification, can mice
そうすれば、人間もマウスも共鳴検証を行うことができます
ok so let's see
わかりました、それでは見てみましょう
can everyone see it? look
みんな見えますか？見てください
This is a normal person, right? What we are doing today
これは普通の人ですよね? 今日私たちがやっていること
Guys, let's do a test, normal people will
みんな、テストをしてみよう、普通の人はそうするだろう
This is a brain thing, I just told everyone
これは脳の問題です、先ほどみんなに言いました
This brain machine is randomly generated in this place
この頭脳マシンはこの場所でランダムに生成されます
Then to protect our whole brain
そして脳全体を守るために
Can you see this?
これが見えますか？
comparatively large
比較大
So if we go to the doctor
それで医者に行ったら
Our doctor took pictures for us
私たちの医師が私たちのために写真を撮ってくれました
He is actually looking at the relevant position of this brain matter.
彼は実際にこの脳の問題の関連する位置を見ています。
abnormal tissue
異常な組織
Are there any areas of the brain that are particularly atrophied?
脳の中で特に萎縮している領域はありますか?
it can be calculated
それは計算できる
What about mice?
ネズミはどうですか？
OK
OK
This is a normal mouse
これは普通のマウスです
look with your eyes
目で見てください
I saw that the mice with this disease will be bigger
この病気にかかったネズミは大きくなることがわかりました
so same problem
同じ問題です
So the little mouse also has a good chord resonance that can be used
したがって、この小さなマウスは、使用できる優れたコード共鳴音も備えています。
Look at the state of brain atrophy
脳の萎縮の状態を見てみましょう
Now there are many brain diseases
今では脳の病気がたくさんあります
Just use compound resonance to see brain atrophy
複合共鳴を使用して脳の萎縮を観察するだけ
or can mark a certain protein
または特定のタンパク質をマークすることができます
let it see the increasing speed
加速する速度を見てみましょう
There is still one
まだ1つあります
what we just saw is that
私たちが今見たのはそれです
motor control disorder
運動制御障害
What about the mouse?
マウスはどうですか？
So this is also a very common
したがって、これも非常に一般的なものです
Everyone sees this scroll wheel
誰もがこのスクロールホイールを見ます
can you see it
見えますか
The rollers are constantly spinning
ローラーは常に回転しています
If the mouse is well balanced enough, it will stay on it
マウスのバランスが取れていればマウスの上に留まります
So which one do you think will fall?
さて、どちらが落ちると思いますか？
i didn't touch that mouse
私はそのマウスに触れませんでした
Just hold on to that wheel so you won't fall off
落ちないようにその車輪をつかんでください
That's not OK
それはダメだよ
Because this depends on its balance
これはバランス次第なので
There is a computer technology
コンピューター技術がある
That is, if it falls
つまり、落ちたら
for example this
たとえばこれ
it falls
落ちる
Let's say technically that it is about a few seconds
厳密に言えば数秒程度だと思います
This mouse is the champion
このマウスがチャンピオンです
it just keeps running like this
このように走り続けるだけです
So this is what we use to look at motor coordination
これが運動調整を調べるために使用されるものです
In contrast we have many lions
対照的に、私たちにはたくさんのライオンがいます
For example, Lions
たとえば、ライオンズ
See if the mouse can find the target
マウスがターゲットを見つけられるかどうかを確認する
And is it going to be tense?
そして緊張するでしょうか？
it will feel helpless
無力感を感じるだろう
it will be anxious
不安になるだろう
This has some analysis to do
これには分析が必要です
Of course whether we believe it or not is another matter
もちろん信じるか信じないかは別問題ですが
Then I introduce one of our
次に、私たちのうちの1つを紹介します
a friend of mine
私の友人
Dr. Zhang Chen
チャン・チェン博士
He told me one day
ある日彼は私に言った
we were chatting and he said
私たちはおしゃべりしていて、彼は言いました
Hey, Yizhuang, let me tell you
ねえ、イーヂュアン、教えてあげましょう
I have new technology recently
最近新しい技術を手に入れた
I can look at the blood vessels of mice
ネズミの血管が見える
I said yes
もちろん
He said bring your mouse and I will do it for you
彼はマウスを持ってきて、私がやってあげると言った
OK
OK
so what
だから何
We started making Huntington's rats
ハンティントンネズミを作り始めました
It looks like we're just having fun, you know
ただ楽しんでるだけみたいだね
is what you see
あなたが見ているものです
Are there many blood vessels?
血管がたくさんあるのでしょうか？
Their technology can be seen
彼らの技術が垣間見えます
Blood vessels as large as 50 to 70micrometer
50～70マイクロメートルもの太い血管
let's guess
推測してみましょう
Is it good or bad to have more blood vessels?
血管が多いことは良いことなのでしょうか、それとも悪いことなのでしょうか？
not necessarily right
必ずしも正しくない
Some people want to say that you just talked about it
あなたはそれについて話したばかりだと言いたい人もいます
This blood vessel can supply energy, right?
この血管はエネルギーを供給できるんですよね？
So we were confused at first
だから私たちも最初は戸惑いました
If we see something like this
このようなものを見たら
what should we do first
まず何をすべきか
The first thing we should do is prove it with a different technique, right?
まず最初にやるべきことは、別の手法で証明することですよね?
right
右
Don't just use MI
MIだけを使用しないでください
MI and holding resonance may just calculate
MIとホールドレゾナンスは計算するだけでよい
so we confirm
それで確認します
Another thing
別物
what you might want to know
あなたが知りたいこと
what about other cells
他の細胞はどうですか
or you might sit there and say
あるいは、そこに座ってこう言うかもしれません
Mr. Cai, you keep talking
蔡さん、話し続けますね
This is a mouse, okay?
これはネズミです、いいですか？
Does that person have
あの人は持っていますか
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
So let me show you
それではお見せしましょう
This is what we just said
これが私たちが今言ったことです
a large number of blood vessels in the brain
脳内の多数の血管
we don't know good or bad
私たちには良いことも悪いこともわかりません
That
それか
just had a suggestion
ちょうど提案がありました
That means it should look at other cells
つまり、他のセルを参照する必要があります
what is the cause
何が原因ですか
Let's ask this first
まずはこれを聞いてみましょう
did we just remember
私たちは思い出しただけですか
Doesn't this glial cell just use his?
このグリア細胞は彼のものを利用しているだけではないでしょうか？
Is it important that the foot wraps the blood vessels?
足が血管を包み込むことが重要ですか？
blood vessels often secrete
血管はしばしば分泌物を分泌します
endothelial growth factor
内皮増殖因子
This promotes angiogenesis
これにより血管新生が促進されます
So we started by saying
そこで私たちはこう言うことから始めました
Is it possible that this has something to do with it?
これが何か関係がある可能性はありますか？
if we think so
私たちがそう思うなら
is there any way to do
何か方法はありますか
The goal is to ask
目的は尋ねることです
Is there something wrong with this glial cell?
このグリア細胞に何か異常があるのでしょうか？
usually in labs like mine
通常、私のような研究室では
How about such a laboratory?
そんな研究室はどうでしょうか？
we'll figure it out
私たちはそれを理解します
This is a blood vessel
これは血管です
We'll find a way to get this glial cell
このグリア細胞を入手する方法を見つけるでしょう
Chuanhua
川華
We'll chop up the little mouse's brain
小さなネズミの脳を切り刻んでやる
and then dissolve it with appeal
そして控訴して解消する
and drop this cell out
このセルを削除します
What about after falling out?
脱落後はどうなるの？
primary neural glial cells
初代神経グリア細胞
Then we can also see some nerve plaques
そうすると神経斑も見えます
really exist in the cells of the disease
病気の細胞の中に実際に存在する
will affect its function
その機能に影響を与えるでしょう
Let's slice the mouse too
ネズミもスライスしてみよう
Let's see if it's because of the growth of the endothelium of the blood vessels.
この血管内皮の増殖が原因かどうかを見てみましょう。
abnormally high volume
異常に大音量
So this is our very common research method
これが私たちの非常に一般的な調査方法です
After we slice the cerebellum
小脳をスライスした後
Stain to find out what glial cells look like
グリア細胞がどのように見えるかを調べるための染色
You can see if it actually looks like its real age?
実際に実年齢と同じかどうかわかりますか？
it looks bigger
大きく見えます
it is exaggerated
それは誇張されています
So it's already overstimulated
つまり、すでに過剰な刺激を受けている
and it has a lot of neuroendothelial growth distributed over it so
神経内皮の成長が多く分布しているため、
So we guess this is the reason
これが理由だと思われます
Do you agree?
同意しますか？
probably no one agrees, right?
おそらく誰も同意しないでしょう？
It's that you can't be like a mouse
それは、ネズミのようにはなれないということです
I can't be like a mouse, can I?
ネズミみたいにはなれないよね？
So when this problem arises
したがって、この問題が発生したとき、
Our first thing is to find the brain slices
最初に行うことは脳のスライスを見つけることです
I'm going to chime in here
ここにチャイムを鳴らします
That is to say we were about ten years ago
つまり10年ほど前は
I just want to make brain pants in Taiwan
台湾でブレインパンツを作りたいだけです
because you said to do this
あなたがこれをすると言ったから
Then someone has to donate their brains
誰かが自分の脳を提供しなければならない
So it is very, very difficult in Taiwan so far
台湾では今のところ非常に困難です
But there are many units abroad
でも海外にはユニットがたくさんある
Including mainland China, it has already started to make brain pants
中国本土を含め、すでにブレインパンツの生産を開始している
Then they collected a lot of patients' brains for slices
それから彼らはスライスのために大量の患者の脳を集めました
So here I can show you
そこで、ここでお見せします
That is to say, research units like ours
つまり、私たちのような研究ユニットは、
I will apply for some brain chips
脳チップを申請します
Then you see that it is actually
そうすれば、それが実際にあることがわかります
Let's say you want the mosquito brain
蚊の脳が欲しいとしましょう
it will appear
それは現れるでしょう
You will apply for this piece with it
この作品と一緒に応募します
Then you put it in the lab to study
それからそれを研究室に置いて研究します
We dye a protein on the outside of blood vessels
血管の外側のタンパク質を染色します
Then you look with your eyes and you will know that there is actually more quantity here
目で見てみると、実際にはもっとたくさんの量があることがわかります。
So in this way we prove
したがって、このようにして証明します
indeed in the human brain
確かに人間の脳内では
Huntington's patient did have more blood vessels
ハンチントン病患者にはより多くの血管があった
We also found that if his brain slices were used to dye
また、彼の脳のスライスが染色に使用された場合、
All you have to do is watch the green signal
あなたがしなければならないのは青信号を監視することだけです
normal people here
ここにいる普通の人たち
Here are the sick people
ここに病人たちがいます
Indeed, the green signal is much stronger.
実際、緑色の信号の方がはるかに強いです。
So this is how we analyze
これが私たちが分析する方法です
Could it be related to this
これと関係あるのかな
Could it be related to this neuroendothelial growth factor?
この神経内皮増殖因子が関係しているのでしょうか？
seems to be related
関連しているようです
Also is there any way to do this part
この部分を実行する他の方法はありますか
recently one i believe
最近私が信じているのは
Because everyone is out there looking at a lot of things
みんな外で色々なことを見ているから
must know this right?
これはわかっているはずですよね？
induced pluripotent cells
誘導された多能性細胞
This has developed from 10 years ago to the present
10年前から現在までの発展
may have a skin
皮があるかもしれない
you have two cc of blood
血液が2ccあります
Some people even say that it can be in urine
尿中に出る可能性があると言う人もいます
He can find out the stem cells that belong to you
彼はあなたの幹細胞を見つけ出すことができます
and convert it to
そしてそれをに変換します
It has to be differentiated in some specific way
何らかの具体的な方法で差別化する必要がある
The way of induction will become ips
誘導方法はipsになります
Then this becomes your cell
そうすれば、これがあなたの細胞になります
you can convert it into nerve cells
神経細胞に変換できる
Glial cells Kidney cells Heart cells
グリア細胞 腎臓細胞 心臓細胞
This is currently being researched by many people in the Academia Sinica
これは現在、中央研究院の多くの人々によって研究されています。
All our Bibles do not have Mr. Xie Qinghe
私たちのすべての聖書には謝清河氏は登場しません
They just want to build up many people in Taiwan
彼らはただ台湾に多くの人を築き上げたいだけなのです
relating documents
関連文書
So you can do a drug screen later
後で薬物スクリーニングを行うことができます
or screening for drug side effects
または薬の副作用のスクリーニング
So what do we neuroscientists do?
それでは、私たち神経科学者は何をするのでしょうか？
for example
例えば
Yes, there is another very important
はい、もう一つ非常に重要なことがあります
Dr. Hongzhi Guo
郭宏志博士
He specializes in the differentiation of nerve cells
彼は神経細胞の分化を専門としています。
Then we also need teamwork
それからチームワークも必要です
For example, a few
たとえば、いくつかの
We have cooperated for many years
私たちは長年にわたって協力してきました
Basically, if you want to do extremely close related research now
基本的に、今非常に密接に関連した研究をしたい場合は、
It must be that the basic colleagues cooperate with the colleagues in the hospital
基本同僚が病院の同僚と協力してるんだろうね
In this case we can put
この場合、次のように置くことができます
There are cells from two normal people and two patients
2人の正常な人々と2人の患者からの細胞があります
differentiate into glial cells
グリア細胞に分化する
It also proved that these glial cells have many
また、これらのグリア細胞には多くの性質があることも証明されました。
Endoglin
エンドグリン
It is also quantifiable
定量化も可能です
We can see that this quantitative result is indeed more
この定量的な結果は実際にはさらに多くの結果であることがわかります。
Using the mouse model
マウスモデルの使用
using human brain
人間の脳を使って
Using glial cells differentiated from humans
ヒトから分化したグリア細胞を利用
can indeed achieve such an effect
確かにそのような効果を達成できます
If we want to study the interaction of two cells
2 つの細胞の相互作用を研究したい場合
We will also use another way
別の方法も使用します
Here it is said that this is a blood vessel
ここは血管だそうです
This is a glial cell
これはグリア細胞です
So we can also make both types of cells
したがって、両方のタイプの細胞を作成することもできます
attack cells
細胞を攻撃する
keep it in an apparatus like this
このような装置の中に保管してください
endothelial cells
こちらが内皮細胞です
Here are the glial cells
こちらがグリア細胞です
let them interact through small molecules
小分子を介して相互作用させます
Let's see if his glial cells are not normal
正常でないグリア細胞を持っているかどうかを確認する
cause excessive growth
過剰な成長を引き起こす
so we can give him a drug
だから私たちは彼に薬を与えることができます
Let him, for example, become colored after entering
たとえば、入った後に彼を色っぽくしてみましょう
Or with radiation we can quantify
あるいは放射線を使えば定量化できる
So it is still quantifiable
したがって、まだ定量化可能です
This is the endothelial cell
これが内皮細胞です
Underneath the culture of normal glial cells
正常なグリア細胞の培養下
it's that growth
それは成長です
This is in the state of glial cells in disease
これは病気のグリア細胞の状態です
so it grows fast
だから成長が早い
That's why it has many, many blood vessels coming out
だから血管がたくさん出ているんです
what is that function
その機能は何ですか
Then this one still has to mention my good friend Zhang Chen
それから、これはまだ私の良き友人であるチャン・チェンについて言及する必要があります
everyone sit here
みんなここに座ってください
In fact, our blood vessels
私たちの血管はどうでしょうか？
Not just responsible for nutrition
栄養を担当するだけではない
It also has a very important role in
また、非常に重要な役割を果たしています
For example, if you go into an environment
たとえば、ある環境に入ると、
Suddenly there are many advantages
いきなりメリットがたくさん出てきた
do you feel uncomfortable sometimes
時々不快に感じますか
what about the mouse what will happen
マウスはどうなりますか？
this picture is missing
この写真がありません
Don't ask everyone to believe this big picture
この全体像を信じるようにみんなに求めないでください
this rat is if you give it
あなたがそれを与えれば、このネズミは
When normal rats are doing this compound resonance experiment,
正常なラットがこの複合共鳴実験を行うと、
you look at its veins
あなたはその血管を見ます
it's here
ここにあります
But a normal mouse
でも普通のマウスは
if you give it carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素を与えると
its blood vessels constrict
その血管が収縮する
But what about sick mice?
しかし、病気のネズミはどうなるでしょうか？
It has many blood vessels, more than it
それ以上に多くの血管があります
Then it doesn't shrink much
そうするとあまり縮まない
So it's about blood vessels
ということで血管の話です
It actually has a function
実は機能があるのです
it will adapt to the outside environment
外部環境に適応していきます
and then adjust the response inside it
そしてその中のレスポンスを調整します
If wet such an effect
濡れればこんな効果も
Maybe it won't work too well
もしかしたらあまりうまくいかないかもしれない
So we just had a
そこで、ちょうど
is what the audience said
視聴者が言ったことです
Blood vessels are not necessarily good or bad
血管は必ずしも良いか悪いかではありません
how to prove this
これをどうやって証明するか
Does it affect physical function?
身体機能に影響はありますか?
We do it very simply
私たちはとてもシンプルにやっています
experiments that a mouse would do
ネズミがやるであろう実験
just open your mind
ただ心を開いてください
Then what
じゃあ何
According to positioning
ポジショニングに応じて
What is the difference between these two?
これら 2 つの違いは何ですか?
This is the location
ここが場所です
After positioning
位置決め後
can be very accurate
非常に正確にできる
For example, today I want to influence
たとえば、今日私が影響を与えたいのは、
is the text
テキストです
specialized control of motor coordination
モーター調整の特殊な制御
i count
私は数えます
my axis
私の軸
I lay down
私は横たわりました
I'll put it in later
後で入れます
Drugs and or Genetic Tools in the Body
体内の薬物や遺伝子ツール
Take this example as
この例を次のように考えます
i can hit a virus
ウイルスに感染する可能性があります
i affect its environment
私はその環境に影響を与えます
At this time, this disease
このとき、この病気は、
would it be better
その方が良いでしょうか
So here is an example
ここに例があります
that is
あれは
we want lentivirus
レンチウイルスが欲しい
carry an anti-inflammatory gene
抗炎症遺伝子を持っている
So we found out that
そこで私たちは次のことを知りました
indeed
それはそう
the number of its blood vessels
血管の数
is down
ダウンしています
And what?
そして何？
its VGF
そのVGF
is also downward
も下向きです
It means that these abnormalities are all due to inflammation
これらの異常はすべて炎症によるものであることを意味します
But more importantly
しかし、もっと重要なことは
This is the movement coordination that we just saw
これが先ほど見た動きの調整です
It's just how a normal mouse can run without falling
これは普通のマウスが落ちずに実行できる方法と同じです
Diseased mice keep falling with the time of onset
病気のマウスは発症時間とともに減少し続ける
At this time, if you give it anti-inflammatory
この時、消炎剤を投与すると、
it can delay the onset
発症を遅らせることができる
So this is what we are developing to treat diseases
これが私たちが病気を治療するために開発しているものです
certain practices
特定の慣行
Then you can imagine that
そうすれば誰もがそう思うでしょう
why can
なぜできるのか
Why getting drugs into the brain is so important
薬物を脳に入れることがなぜそれほど重要なのか
because i don't know how you are
あなたの様子がわからないから
I don't really want to open a hole in my brain
脳に穴を開けたくない
Then take a medicine every month
それから毎月薬を飲みます
because it's actually difficult
実際には難しいから
Of course there are many people now
もちろん今も人がたくさんいます
Due to the relationship of last resort, this method is being developed
最終手段の関係上、この方法が開発されています
But this is a lab like ours
でもここは私たちのような研究室です
We'll use it to study drugs and
薬物の研究に使用します
A method with its pathological mechanism
病理メカニズムを考慮した手法
so finally
それでついに
I'm almost done reporting
ほぼ報告終わりました
Finally our conclusion is
最終的に私たちの結論は、
That is to say, in this disease
つまり、この病気では
His neurons secrete too much angiogenin
彼のニューロンはアンジオゲニンを過剰に分泌する
These blood vessels are actually incompetent
これらの血管は実際には無力です
Well, if we stop this from happening,
さて、これが起こらないようにするなら、
He'll stop voice degeneration
彼は声の退化を止めるだろう
Everyone sitting here wants to say
ここに座っている全員が言いたいのは
Wow, how do you say this in Taiwanese?
わあ、これは台湾語で何と言いますか？
Is public water port communication
公共水港通信です
What is the importance of talking for half a day?
半日話すことの重要性は何ですか？
We are developing this while
私たちはこの間開発を行っています
We actually don't know if you think
実際にあなたがそう思っているかどうかはわかりません
is he important
彼は何か重要な人物ですか
what do we see
私たちには何が見えますか
We don't actually want to publish that paper
私たちは実際にはその論文を出版したくないのですが、
Of course we have to publish papers
もちろん論文も出版しなければなりません
otherwise we will be in trouble
そうでないと私たちは困ってしまいます
importance has one
重要性は 1 つあります
Do you think
思いますか？
That MRI angiography
そのMRI血管造影
Is it an invasive or non-invasive room
それは侵襲的な部屋ですか、それとも非侵襲的な部屋ですか
Does the non-invasive room work?
非侵襲室は機能しますか?
today if we can use
今日使えるなら
This disease can be used if
この病気は次の場合に使用できます。
Non-invasive chamber to observe disease development
疾患の進行を観察するための非侵襲的チャンバー
will it be
そうなるだろうか
So there are several important
したがって、重要なことがいくつかあります
One is that we just talked about understanding the pathological mechanism
1つは、病理学的メカニズムの理解についてお話ししたばかりです。
what we just said
私たちが今言ったこと
So maybe in the long run
だから、もしかしたら長期的には
Maybe look for some inhibitors
おそらく阻害剤を探すかもし​​れません
new drugs to suppress the mechanism
メカニズムを抑制する新薬
Then our lentivirus just now
それから私たちのレンチウイルスは今
it's not good, isn't it?
それは良くないですよね？
because you don't want to punch a hole in your brain
脳に穴を開けたくないから
so not so good
あまり良くない
But if we can find
でももし見つけられたら
Drugs that can cross the blood-brain barrier
血液脳関門を通過できる薬剤
maybe solve a problem
もしかしたら問題が解決するかもしれない
So understanding the mechanics has its specific importance
したがって、メカニズムを理解することは特に重要です
Second, can we find biomarkers?
第二に、バイオマーカーを見つけることができるでしょうか?
This can tell everyone
これは誰にでも言える
This is the part that makes us sad
これが私たちを悲しくさせる部分です
you develop a drug
あなたは薬を開発します
Then you go talk to the manufacturer
それからメーカーに相談してみます
You said I found a great drug
すごい薬を見つけたって言ってたね
He immediately asked you
彼はすぐにあなたに尋ねました
when did you work
いつ働きましたか
when do you want a biomarker
いつバイオマーカーが必要ですか
tell me a month
1ヶ月教えてください
Herein lies the difficulty of neurodegenerative disease
神経変性疾患の難しさはここにあります
because of degradation
劣化のため
even our dearest family
私たちの最愛の家族でさえも
It takes a while before you know if he's degenerated
彼が退化しているかどうかがわかるまでには時間がかかる
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
we go to the hospital
私たちは病院に行きます
If you have experience
経験のある方なら
You know the hospital has complicated
病院が複雑なのはご存知でしょう
Cognitive system to tell you
あなたに伝える認知システム
Have your elders degenerated
先輩たちは堕落したのか
so
それで
Is there a good biomarker
良いバイオマーカーはありますか
He's actually a drug developer
実は彼は麻薬開発者だった
very important opportunity
非常に重要な機会
so this part
それでこの部分
In the future we also hope to have some
将来的には、いくつかのことも期待しています
good research
良い研究
Go in to assist in drug development
医薬品開発を手伝うために行く
The third point is also interesting
3点目も興味深い
I just don't know if I have experience
ただ経験があるかどうかは分かりません
sometimes
時々
We will take our mother-in-law to the doctor
私たちは義母を医者に連れて行きます
The doctor said very carefully
医者はとても慎重に言った
This old man's drug use is different
この老人の薬物使用は違う
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
We just saw some blood vessels
ほんの少し血管が見えました
It's better if you don't have blood vessels
血管が無い方が良い
he may be different
彼は違うかもしれない
So these vascular diseases
したがって、これらの血管疾患は
May cause some metabolic abnormalities
何らかの代謝異常を引き起こす可能性がある
So there will be a difference in the use of drugs
そうすると薬の使い方にも違いが出てくる
We have a very good colleague named Professor Lin Junrong at National Taiwan University
私たちには国立台湾大学のリン・ジュンロン教授というとても良い同僚がいます。
They later worked with us on a job
彼らはその後私たちと一緒に仕事をしました
also published a paper on
に関する論文も発表しました
on this disease
この病気について
In fact, we believe that many diseases are like this
実際、多くの病気がこれに似ていると私たちは考えています
when the brain is inflamed
脳が炎症を起こしているとき
There is a protein in the brain called PGP
脳にはPGPというタンパク質がある
Specially expel drugs out of the blood vessels
血管から薬剤を特別に排出する
so you thought you ate a
それで食べたと思ったの？
But actually it pushes you out a bit
でも実際には、それはあなたを少し押しのけます
So the amount left in the brain is what matters
つまり脳内にどれだけ残っているかが重要なのです
But in this neurodegenerative disease
しかし、この神経変性疾患では
Inside our mouse model
マウスモデルの内部
It is due to the sharp increase in the amount
金額が大幅に上がったためです
change the dosage of the drug
薬の投与量を変更する
So this is also very important in future use
したがって、これは将来の使用においても非常に重要です
So today I am very happy thank you all for giving me this opportunity
だから今日はとても幸せです、このような機会を与えてくれた皆さんに感謝します
to report research on glial cells
グリア細胞に関する研究を報告する
Thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
It's not easy for everyone to listen so late
誰もがこんなに遅くまで聞くのは簡単ではありません
We feel like we really need to work together
私たちは本当に協力する必要があると感じています
I hope you can give us some suggestions in the future
今後も何かご提案をいただければ幸いです
What can we do to tell Academia Sinica
中央研究院に伝えるために何ができるか
we will try our best
私たちは最善を尽くします
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you Special Researcher Chen Yizhuang for his speech
特別研究員のChen Yizhuang氏の講演に感謝します
We're now open for questions
質問を受け付けています
Is there anyone who has a problem?
困っている人はいますか？
please
お願いします
ask the professor
教授に聞く
They are all researching what medicines will have effective treatment.
どのような薬が治療に効果的かを皆で研究しました。
Can you give us some
いくつかいただけますか
how to try to prevent
どのように予防しようとするか
Thanks
ありがとう
I really want to say this
本当はこれが言いたいのですが
I really want to answer this
本当はこれに答えたいのですが
but i'm a little scared
でも少し怖いです
it's how i do myself
それが私自身のやり方です
say hello to you
あなたに挨拶してください
because i'm not a doctor
私は医者ではないので
So I can't really
だから本当にできない
make any medical advice
医学的なアドバイスをする
but i personally
しかし私は個人的に
i personally really believe
私は個人的に本当に信じています
Exercise must be good
運動は良いはずです
Everyone knows that now there is a person called that
今ではそう呼ばれる人がいることは誰もが知っています
myotrophic factor
筋萎縮因子
They study very enthusiastically in the United States
彼らはアメリカでとても熱心に勉強しています
it's you every day
それは毎日あなたです
If you exercise three times a week
週に3回運動する場合
30 minutes each time
毎回30分
then you hit a heartbeat
それからあなたは鼓動を打ちます
what 130 times
何と130回
In fact, your whole body's blood and brain
実際、体中には血液と脳が流れています。
Interaction will be better
インタラクションが良くなる
There is one called BDNF
BDNFと呼ばれるものがあります
nerve growth factor
神経成長因子
will be more
もっとなるだろう
they studied
彼らは研究した
You know rats go and run for an hour and come back
ネズミは1時間行っては走って戻ってくるのを知っていますよね
analyze it
それを分析する
It was found that there are more growth factors in the
さらに多くの成長因子が存在することが分かりました。
I believe it myself
私自身それを信じています
so i often do sports
だから私はよくスポーツをします
This is a
これは
sleep well everyone
みんなよく寝てね
I think it's possible
可能だと思います
not too many people want to stay up all night
徹夜したい人はあまり多くない
That young people please don't stay up late
若い人たちは夜更かししないでください
Frequent
頻繁
It means maintenance should start from young
メンテナンスは若いうちから始めるべきだということです
sleep well
よく眠る
Don't use too many drugs or other things that cause high oxidative stress
高い酸化ストレスを引き起こす薬物やその他のものを多量に使用しないでください。
professor
教授
Share what exercise you do because you look younger than five or four
5歳か4歳よりも若く見えるため、どのような運動をしているかを共有してください
There are all kinds of sports in our Central Plains, which is very good.
私たちの中原にはあらゆる種類のスポーツがあり、とても良いです。
Sportscenter
運動中心
The swimming pool is very good, the treadmill is very good, please pay attention to safety
スイミングプールはとても良く、トレッドミルもとても良いです。安全には注意してください。
Treadmills are good because these increase the oxygen levels in the protocol
トレッドミルは、プロトコル内の酸素レベルを増加させるため、優れています。
In fact, the detailed reason for this seems to be not completely clear from recent research.
実は、その詳しい理由は最近の研究でも完全には解明されていないようです。
So all I can tell you is that I really believe this
だから私に言えるのは、私はこれを本当に信じているということだけです
So if you're not fit for running
したがって、ランニングに適していない場合は、
like my husband is doing
私の夫がしているように
come study me today
今日は私を勉強しに来てください
How about he doesn't like running so he takes a walk
彼は走るのが好きではないので散歩したらどうでしょうか
It's good to walk and swim
歩いたり泳いだりするのは良いことです
Sometimes it doesn't take too long to walk for half an hour
30分歩くのにそれほど時間がかからないこともあります
Actually all pretty good
実際にはどれもかなり良い
I believe this is supposed to work like this
これはこのように機能するはずだと信じています
Thanks
ありがとう
Excuse me, teacher, I would like to ask you
すみません、先生、お願いしたいのですが
about the beginning of the previous
前回の始まりについて
You mentioned a story about some nerve-related diseases that come from
あなたは、いくつかの神経関連疾患が原因であるという話をしました。
Neuron upstream of it may be too active
その上流のニューロンが活動しすぎる可能性があります
Because it cannot be ruled out later
後々の可能性も否定できないので
right
右
then i want a little
それから少し欲しいです
I don't know if I can ask the teacher to
先生に聞いてもいいのか分かりません
Just a little bit more about what caused the
原因についてもう少し詳しく説明すると、
Because you just said it was because of CSF
だって、CSFのせいだとさっき言ったから
It's the one that can't be ruled out.
それは除外できないものです。
hyperactivation
過活動
what kind of idea is this
これはどのようなアイデアですか
Thanks
ありがとう
thanks for your question
ご質問ありがとうございます
In fact, I may have spoken too fast when I spoke just now.
実際、私が今話したときは早口すぎたかもしれません。
So I have several things connected together
だから私はいくつかのものを一緒に接続しています
in many neurological diseases
多くの神経疾患において
what happened was
何が起こったのか
For example, this nerve has been functioning
たとえば、この神経は機能しています
Discharge all the time
常に放電する
That would have been good to discharge
退院すればよかった
i see you
あなたが見えてます。
It's good if I send a message
メッセージ送っても良いですよ
But when the news spread for a long time
しかし、そのニュースが長期間にわたって広まると、
many times
何度も
It causes the cells inside the
それは細胞の
Calcium hyperactivation
カルシウムの活性化亢進
and then initiates a neuronal death mechanism
そして神経細胞死のメカニズムを開始します
There could be many reasons for this
これには多くの理由が考えられます
include
含む
For example, some
たとえば、いくつかの
specific genetic inheritance
特定の遺伝的継承
lesion etc.
病変など
Also when we
また、私たちが
For example, when you are older
たとえば、年をとったとき、
maybe this
たぶんこれ
When the regulation of calcium ions is not so good
カルシウムイオンの調節がうまくいかない場合
also cause these problems
こういった問題も引き起こします
receptors between these nerve cells
これらの神経細胞の間にある受容体
I don't even have a chance to talk to you today
今日はあなたと話す機会さえありません
These also cause big problems
これらも大きな問題を引き起こします
However, exclusion of hydrocephalus
ただし水頭症は除く
This thing is supported by the system
これはシステムでサポートされています
these are two different things
これらは2つの異なるものです
In principle
原則上
the brain fluid we just talked about
先ほど話した脳液について
just smooth
ただ滑らかな
Every day we can get 500CC
毎日500CCを獲得できます
Our brains work hard
私たちの脳は一生懸命働きます
discharge out
排出する
Now everybody sits here like me
今、誰もが私と同じようにここに座っています
Hydrocephalus fluid up to 120CC in the brain
脳内の最大120CCの水頭症の液体
It actually keeps our function
それは実際に私たちの機能を維持します
As long as it is successfully ruled out
それがうまく排除されている限り
In fact, the problem is very small
実際、問題は非常に小さなものです
Now I'm just afraid
今はただ怖いだけです
The A-beta we just talked about has some bad proteins
先ほど話したAベータには悪いタンパク質が含まれています
it just piles up there
そこに溜まっていくだけだ
start a little
少し始める
Later more and more
後はどんどん
that would cause the lesion we just saw
それは私たちが今見た病変を引き起こすでしょう
thank you for asking me
質問してくれてありがとう
so i can make it clearer
だから私はそれをより明確にすることができます
Mr. Chen, I have two questions
チェンさん、2つ質問があります。
The first question is to say
最初の質問はこう言います
When the Harrington system is
ハリントンシステムの場合
There are two of them, one is normal and the other is not normal
それらは 2 つあり、1 つは正常で、もう 1 つは正常ではありません
in abnormal times
異常な時代に
its blood vessels grow excessively
血管が過剰に成長する
Then you have compared the two grown blood vessels
次に、成長した 2 つの血管を比較しました。
what's the difference
違いは何ですか
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
The second question I am very interested in is to say
私が非常に興味のある 2 番目の質問は、次のとおりです。
D-Geezer at Aceves
アセベスのD-Geezer
It's Microclean
マイクロクリーンです
usually
いつもの
It is incapable of removing those proteins
それらのタンパク質を除去することはできません
then why
それでなんで
Cause we know stuff like Marco Farge
だって私たちはマルコ・ファージのようなことを知っているから
In fact it only knows to clear
実際にはクリアすることだけを知っています
but ask it to clear something
でも何かをクリアするために頼む
It's actually something else talking to it.
実際には、別の何かが話しかけているのです。
On this mechanism, what new breakthroughs have been made in the recent research on SAN
このメカニズムに関して、最近の SAN の研究ではどのような新たな進歩が見られましたか
Honorington disease, what is the difference in its blood vessels
オノリントン病、血管の違いは何ですか
That's what we really want to know
それが私たちが本当に知りたいことです
That's why we do vasoconstriction
だから血管収縮をするのです
Now it looks like the first of them are neovascularization
現在、最初の症状は血管新生であるようです
because we can see signs of new blood vessels
新しい血管の兆候が見えるからです
But the blood also passes through
でも血液も通る
The blood flow is also considered normal, but it does not reflect the environment
血流も正常とみなされますが、環境を反映していません。
That is to say, if the environment has a lot of carbon dioxide, it cannot react
つまり、環境に二酸化炭素が多量にある場合、反応することができません。
So I just didn't say a little bit because I didn't want to make everyone feel super boring
だから、みんなを超退屈にさせたくなかったので、少ししか言わなかったんだ
It is the contraction of blood vessels that requires muscle
血管の収縮には筋肉が必要です
It has a cell called parasite
寄生虫と呼ばれる細胞がいる
When those cells are inflamed, they die very quickly
これらの細胞は炎症を起こすとすぐに死んでしまいます
so those cells die
それでそれらの細胞は死ぬ
So why did I have a
それで、なぜ私は
Anti-inflammation his death was not so serious
抗炎症 彼の死はそれほど深刻ではなかった
So he can still shrink
だから彼はまだ縮むことができる
So overall we just saw that
全体的に見て、私たちはそれを確認しました
or an inflammatory reaction
または炎症反応
The point you just mentioned is also very important
今おっしゃった点も非常に重要です
It is the perigelatin cells in the treatment syndrome
治療症候群におけるペリゼラチン細胞です
That's because after the loss of perigelatin function
それはペリゼラチンの機能が失われた後だからです。
He can't eat that bad protein
彼はそんな悪いタンパク質は食べられない
we just mentioned
先ほど言いました
Well, he's actually a little serious
まあ、彼は実際には少し真面目です
It is he who releases a large amount of
大量に放出するのは彼です
satocide
サトサイド
Sorry, I forgot what Satocide is called
ごめん、サトサイドって何て言うか忘れた
Thanks for cell base
セルベースをありがとう
cell base
細胞基盤
You have heard that during SARS
SARSの時に聞いたことがあるでしょう
Many people die because of what
多くの人が何のせいで死ぬのか
It is the Satocide storm
サトサイドの嵐だ
in the brain too
脳の中にも
You have too many of these cell bases would have been good
これらの細胞基地が多すぎると良いでしょう
now it's bad
今はダメだ
So we can see that in
したがって、それを見ることができます
nerve pain disease
神経痛の病気
Many people are using anti-inflammatory
抗炎症剤を使用している人が多い
The goal is to reduce the base of his secreting cells
目標は、分泌細胞の基礎を減らすことです
So now it looks like trying to reduce the damage to neurons
つまり、ニューロンへのダメージを軽減しようとしているようです
Especially we just said that neural network connection
特にニューラルネットワーク接続については先ほど述べました。
i connected to you
私はあなたとつながりました
Then if I can't connect with you, I don't have this memory
それであなたと繋がれないなら、私にはこの記憶がない
So this piece is also affected by many of these small
したがって、この作品もこれらの小さなことの多くの影響を受けています
It is the effect of small plaques of Aβ
Aβの小さなプラークの影響です
This becomes serious when it can't be cleared
クリアできないと大変なことになる
Thank you
ありがとう
I ask for advice
アドバイスを求めます
Since sleep is so important
睡眠はとても大事なので
As I said just now, there will be some external things to stimulate
先ほども言いましたが、外部から刺激を受けるものがいくつかあります。
cause poor sleep
睡眠不足を引き起こす
Can I take sleeping pills?
睡眠薬を服用してもいいですか？
Because it's webcast and recorded
ウェブ放送と録画なので
so i don't
だから私はしません
I am joking
私は冗談を言っています
I dare not answer casually
気軽に答える勇気はない
but i can tell you my personal opinion
でも私の個人的な意見を言えます
In fact, I just didn't have to imagine
実際、想像する必要はなかった
just afraid of causing this problem
この問題を引き起こすのが怖いだけです
you know it's fun
それが楽しいことは知っていますね
not you asleep
あなたは眠っていません
that your cells will become less
細胞が少なくなるということ
Then the space will be bigger
そしたらスペースも広くなるよ
it has sleeping pills
睡眠薬が入っている
like anesthesia
麻酔のような
That is, it will circulate better
つまり循環が良くなるのです
Then why don't you know now
じゃあなぜ今は分からないのか
That study we just saw
たった今見たその研究
very interesting
とても興味深い
It's actually just two or three years of research
実際にはわずか2、3年の研究です
I don't know what the reason is
理由はわかりません
So to answer your question
あなたの質問に答えるには
theoretically possible
理論的には可能
But there's a serious problem behind it sleeping pills
しかし、その背後には睡眠薬の深刻な問題があります
so really not recommended
なので本当にお勧めしません
If there is a problem, colleagues
問題があれば同僚
I am not a colleague
私は同僚ではありません
friends who have problems
問題を抱えた友達
I think it's time to talk to the doctor
医者に相談する時期が来たと思う
Finding a way to sleep naturally should be better
自然に眠る方法を見つけた方が良いはずです
right
右
The professor from that country has a question
あの国の教授に質問がある
You just talked about the aging problem in Taiwan
先ほど台湾の高齢化問題についてお話しましたね
we have a book club
私たちは読書クラブを持っています
are old people
老人です
There are 20 adults now
現在大人は20名です
Parents of 8 of them
そのうち8人の親たち
can't rule life
人生を支配することはできない
Some live in nursing homes
老人ホームに住んでいる人もいる
4 of them are Shi Yizheng
そのうちの4人はShi Yizhengです
So this ratio
つまりこの比率は
Although we are little Wu parents
私たちは小さなウーの両親ですが、
but no specific
しかし具体的ではない
So anyone can come to this reading club
誰でもこの読書会に来てください
so serious
真剣
The other 4 people with Shi Yizheng
石宜正と他の4人
They told us that Shi Yizheng
彼らは私たちに、Shi Yizhen がこう言ったのです。
it happened only one night
それはたった一晩の出来事だった
Then slowly the progress will be 8 years
それからゆっくりと進歩は8年になります
Freed after 8 years
8年ぶりに釈放される
nothing left
何も残らなかった
how do you do this
これどうやってやるの
Why did it happen in one day
なぜ一日でそうなったのか
Thanks
ありがとう
or i'm not a doctor
あるいは私は医者ではありません
but still my personal opinion
しかし、それでも私の個人的な意見
actually not usually
実際には通常はそうではありません
one day usually not
ある日、通常はそうではない
Usually not, sometimes we just
通常はそうではありませんが、時々
And especially I think everyone here falls into this category
そして特にここにいる人は全員がこのカテゴリーに当てはまると思います
the smarter you are
あなたが賢ければ賢いほど
the higher your education
学歴が高ければ高いほど
It's harder for others to find out
他の人には見つけられにくい
we are demented
私たちは認知症です
Because it will be hidden, right?
隠蔽されるからですよね？
you can easily find it in other ways
他の方法で簡単に見つけることができます
suddenly one day
ある日突然
there is no way to control
制御する方法はありません
But actually the process is slow
しかし実際にはプロセスが遅い
Then we have some very
それから、とても良いものがあります
well done research
よくできた研究
For example that
たとえば、
dementia research
認知症研究
We combined Beirong's research with their
私たちは Beirong の研究と彼らの研究を組み合わせました。
It's not mine, it's Academia Sinica's
それは私のものではありません、中央研究院のものです
They discovered that there is actually another one called MCI in the middle.
彼らは、実際には真ん中に MCI と呼ばれる別のものが存在することを発見しました。
It's just a slight problem with cognitive function.
認知機能に少し問題があるだけです。
And then they're doing it now and trying to find
そして彼らは今それをやっていて、見つけようとしています
Ability to have problems with cognitive function
認知機能に問題がある可能性
to real dementia
本格的な認知症に
Is there a way to turn around in the middle
途中で折り返す方法はありますか
You can turn around there
そこで振り向いてもいいよ
But once you enter dementia
しかし、認知症に入ると、
maybe
多分
current
現在的
there is no way
道はない
You're not actually a day, definitely not the middle of a day
あなたは実際には一日ではありません、間違いなく一日の途中ではありません
The middle process is very long
中間工程が非常に長い
then we are our good friends
それなら私たちは良い友達です
We can observe ourselves and take care of ourselves
私たちは自分自身を観察し、自分自身の世話をすることができます
have some minor symptoms
軽い症状がある
Remember to exercise more
もっと運動することを忘れないでください
I'm still going to say that
まだそう言うつもりだよ
do more of that
それをもっとやれ
For example, listening to speeches is fine.
たとえば、スピーチを聞くのは問題ありません。
But in our problem
しかし、私たちの問題では
the parents of twenty
二十歳の両親
There should be forty parents
親は40人いるはずだ
But some earlier
しかし、もう少し前に
These peanuts are very old
これらのピーナッツはとても古いものです
But this ratio is also very high
しかし、この比率も非常に高いです
Are you stable with your acting skills?
演技力は安定してる？
Let's talk about Taiwan's program
台湾のプログラムについて話しましょう
Yeah, actually we just saw
ええ、実はちょうど見たところなのです
this is very worrying
これはとても心配です
That's why I thought I should come in and do some research.
だからこそ、入って調べてみようと思ったのです。
His proportion will be higher and higher
彼の割合はますます高くなるだろう
especially i want you to know
特に知っておいてほしい
That life in Taiwan
その台湾での生活
Both men and women are approaching eighty
男も女も80歳に近づいている
I'm thinking, maybe when I'm late
遅くなったらかなと思ってます
close to eighty
80近い
close to 90%
90%近く
Half of the people will have this problem
半数の人がこの問題を抱えているでしょう
That's why we really want to strengthen both parts
だからこそ、私たちは両方の部分を本当に強化したいのです
one is research
一つは研究です
The other one is actually Changzhao and Guanghuai.
もう一つは実際には長昭と広淮です。
understand the disease
病気を理解する
I think this part will be very important to the whole society in the future
この部分は今後社会全体にとって非常に重要になると思います
Thank you very much for bringing it up
取り上げていただきまして誠にありがとうございます
In addition, it means that the treatment of symptoms is actually
また、実際に症状を治療するということは、
many kinds
多種
Not certainly
確かにそうではない
It doesn't have to be alzheimer disease, there are other kinds
必ずしもアルツハイマー病というわけではなく、他の種類もあります
It's hard to tell
伝えるのは難しい
Degeneration is the main reason
退化が主な原因
Thank you
ありがとう
Mr. Chen, let me ask you
チェンさん、質問させてください。
sleep problems
睡眠の問題
I personally was
私は個人的にそうでした
Everyone I think this is commentary
皆さん、これはコメントだと思います
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
Some people just don't sleep well
ただよく眠れない人もいる
Does it mean that these people are the so-called
この人たちはいわゆる
risk group
リスクグループ
Is there such a tendency
そういう傾向あるのかな
That is to say, he is easier to get
つまり彼は手に入れやすい
because he is old
彼は年をとっているので
Some people with poor sleep quality
睡眠の質が悪い人もいる
from a young age
幼い頃から
I don't know why, but I just can't sleep well
なぜか分からないけどよく眠れない
that you just mentioned
あなたが今言ったこと
Sleeping pills may also help
睡眠薬も効くかもしれない
then we'll rule it out
それからそれを除外します
But many people have poor sleep from a young age
しかし、多くの人は若い頃から睡眠不足に悩まされています
So my question is
それで私の質問は
Can these people be classified as dangerous groups?
これらの人々は危険なグループとして分類できますか?
Yes, I think there is a high possibility of what you are talking about
はい、あなたの言っていることはその可能性が高いと思います
maybe later
おそらく後で
Maybe we in Taiwan should carefully study this matter
私たち台湾人はこの問題を注意深く研究する必要があるかもしれません
Because neurodegeneration usually happens very late
神経変性は通常非常に遅くに起こるため
We are only now starting to build
私たちは今、構築を始めたばかりです
For example, the systematic collection
たとえば、体系的なコレクション
It's about some things related to restraint syndrome.
それは拘束症候群に関連するいくつかのことについてです。
BioMarket in blood including brain
脳を含む血液中のバイオマーケット
biomarkers and more
バイオマーカーなど
I think the quality of sleep in the future
これからの睡眠の質は
Maybe this should be included
もしかしたらこれも含めるべきかもしれない
Thank you for reminding
思い出させてくれてありがとう
I'm going to talk to my good friend Wang Shujun again.
親友の王樹君ともう一度話します。
thank you
ありがとう
Professor, you just mentioned that you slept well
先生、よく眠れたとおっしゃいましたね
I didn't sleep well when I was young
若い頃はよく眠れなかった
but
しかし
I later because of a change in life
その後、生活の変化により
I sleep less
睡眠時間が短くなりました
Now
現在
but i lie down
でも私は横になります
i may fall asleep soon
すぐに眠ってしまうかもしれない
I'm bound to wake up in five or six hours
5、6時間後には目が覚めるはずだ
that is
あれは
I may not know what's going on among me
自分の中で何が起こっているのか分からないかもしれない
but i woke up
でも目が覚めた
I'm probably like this all the time
たぶんいつもこんな感じだよ
but i slept
でも寝た
I think I'm strong enough
私は十分強いと思う
so good
とても良い
Sleeping eyebrows are of good quality
寝眉は質が良い
still sleep
まだ寝ています
I just can't sleep long enough
十分に長く眠れないだけです
but my doctor
でも私の医者
sometimes my doctor will tell you
時々私の医者はあなたに言うでしょう
you need to sleep for eight hours
あなたは8時間眠る必要があります
but i can't help it
でも仕方ない
in eight hours
8時間以内に
I actually spent hours
実際に何時間も費やしました
I'm awake in bed
私はベッドで起きています
like this
このような
Is everyone's situation different?
皆の状況は違うのでしょうか？
this is the doctor
これが医者です
We all hate what doctors say
私たちは皆、医師の言うことが嫌いです
just everyone is different
ただみんなが違うだけ
But it's actually true
でもそれは実際に真実なのです
Do you know about love?
愛について知っていますか？
only slept for four hours
4時間しか寝なかった
right
右
i have a colleague
同僚がいます
He's great at the clinic
彼はクリニックでは素晴らしいです
will do anything
何でもします
He also sleeps for four hours
彼も4時間寝ます
post a lot
たくさん投稿する
So it really depends on the individual situation.
したがって、それは実際には個々の状況に依存します。
then if you think everything is fine
それですべてがうまくいくと思うなら
you are not sick or what
あなたは病気でも何でもありません
maybe he is the best for you
たぶん彼はあなたにとって最高です
I really don't think time is the biggest issue
時間が最大の問題だとは本当に思わない
mainly quality
主に品質
Like we just said it's no use having a big brain
先ほども言ったように、大きな頭脳があっても無駄です
This is to connect like this
このように接続するのです
It should be mentioned that the antibody part comes from the stock market ruling
抗体の部分は株式市場の判決に由来していることに言及する必要があります。
This should be mentioned from the public climate of the central stock market
これは中央株式市場の世論からも言及されるべきである
from fat shoulders
太い肩から
So how do anti-stockholders who want to fight against stock market?
では、株式市場と闘いたい反株主はどうすればいいのでしょうか？
The second type is the fat bladder. The fat bladder is
2 番目のタイプは脂肪膀胱です。
We have limbs with fat arms at the center
私たちは手足を中心に太い腕を持っています
like wanton limbs
乱暴な手足のように
it needs to put its belly on
腹を立てる必要がある
You will pass the stock market stocks on this place
この場所で株式市場の株式を渡します
Why should we look at it?
なぜそれを見る必要があるのでしょうか？
yes, that's a very powerful question
はい、それは非常に強力な質問です
Two questions, one is to say
質問は 2 つありますが、1 つは次のことです。
This can't pass the blood brain, the wall is swollen, what are you playing, right?
これは血液脳を通過できません、壁が腫れています、何を遊んでいますか？
In fact, many people are discussing this part
実際、多くの人がこの部分について議論しています
There is a saying that everyone knows that
誰もが知っているという言葉があります
Are the rows not clean?
列がきれいではありませんか?
When it is discharged, if your blood goes out
排出されるとき、血液が出なくなると
This big reservoir theory is in the blood
この大きな貯水池理論は血液の中にあります
If you have antibodies, it will help you by the way
抗体持ってれば助かるよ
get rid of you is a way of saying
あなたを追い出すというのは言い方です
What are other people doing?
他の人は何をしているのですか？
He put his antibody on top of a can
彼は自分の抗体を缶の上に置いた
A small molecular elite engineered to turn over blood vessels
血管をひっくり返すように設計された小さな分子エリート
they think it can be turned over
彼らはそれをひっくり返すことができると考えている
antibodies in the brain
脳内の抗体
Go in and get rid of this plaque
入ってこのプラークを取り除きましょう
Like the article in June this year
今年6月の記事のように
I told everyone
みんなに言いました
It's so mysterious that they've been doing it for eighteen months
彼らが18ヶ月もそれを続けているのはとても神秘的です
plaques in their brains
脳内のプラーク
is lowered
下げられています
you know we all say
私たち皆が言うことを知っていますか
don't believe it
信じないでください
Of course the stock price went up again like this
もちろんこのまま株価はまた上がりました
so
それで
I don't know this either
これも分からない
Because the drug just 27 years ago
なぜなら、この薬はちょうど27年前のものだからです。
exist
存在
A year or two ago, everyone thought it would be a success
1～2年前は誰もが成功すると思っていた
so
それで
But there are various people doing various designs
でも、いろんな人がいろんなデザインをやっているんです
In the long run I think it will be successful
長い目で見れば成功すると思う
it's funny you just asked a question
面白いですね、今質問したのに
you say
あなたは言う
Then can I find someone without a blood brain?
では、血液脳を持たない人を見つけることはできるのでしょうか？
The place where the wall is bulging is fine
壁が盛り上がっているところは大丈夫です
Do you know what medicine?
何の薬か知っていますか？
Do you have a face and nasal cavity?
顔と鼻腔はありますか？
i told you heard
聞いたと言いました
It's the nasal cavity going up from here
ここから上がっていくのが鼻腔です
That
それか
Put some drugs that are not easy to enter the blood and brain wall
血液や脳壁に入りにくい薬を入れる
why not
なぜだめですか
just click in
クリックするだけです
it goes in
それは入ります
so now there are some
だから今はいくつかあります
Research colleagues are doing this
研究仲間がこれをやっている
that was very successful in mice
それはマウスでは大成功でした
We have a colleague named Dupont County
デュポン・カウンティという名前の同僚がいます
Chen Peiyan
チェン・ペイヤン
they do things like this
彼らはこのようなことをします
They click into the small PAPTITE
小さなパプタイトにカチッとはまる
Then
それから
the mouse one
マウスのもの
Evidence is much better
証拠ははるかに優れています
but
しかし
you know that mouse has a big nose
ネズミの鼻が大きいことは知っていますね
human nose is small
人間の鼻は小さい
This is only half a skid why
これは半分しか滑っていないのですが、なぜですか？
Because it's true, the mouse part is very
本当ですので、マウス部分は非常に
It's really big. It's the whole head. The person is very small.
それは本当に大きいです、それは頭全体です、そしてその人はとても小さいです。
Although the effect is actually everyone is still watching
実際にはまだみんなが見ている効果はありますが
But there are indeed some medicines that go in this way from this section
しかし、このセクションからこのように進むいくつかの薬は確かにあります
yes very good idea
はい、とても良いアイデアです
It looks like a classmate of you has been trying to ask me a question, right?
あなたのクラスメイトが私に質問しようとしているようですよね？
I'm sorry, I just want to ask about the sleep just now
すみません、今の睡眠について聞きたいのですが
I seem to have seen it in Science Daily before.
以前サイエンスデイリーで見たような気がします。
It's not good if you sleep too long
寝すぎると良くないよ
I don't know why that's why sleeping too much happens and is it a good thing
理由は分かりません、だから寝過ぎが起こるのですが、それは良いことなのでしょうか？
The second one is for the half of the brain.
2つ目は脳の半分です。
There is another kind of
別の種類もあります
I just saw another group of medical scientists discussing before
以前、別の医学者グループが議論しているのを見たばかりです
Sui Pryon's series of diseases
スイ・プリオンの一連の病気
The kind we are generally familiar with
私たちが一般的によく知っている種類
It's normal like the non-infectious kind
非感染性の種類と同じように正常です
What is the difference between the lesion in half of the brain?
脳の半分の病変との違いは何ですか?
your question now
今のあなたの質問
Because I was actually discussing the issue just now
実は今その問題について話し合っていたところだったので、
i was thinking
私が考えていた
I actually read a newspaper that said
実際に読んだ新聞にはこう書かれていました
if you sleep eight hours
8時間寝たら
life gets shorter or something
寿命が短くなるとかなんとか
so someone is talking
それで誰かが話している
Even sleeping too much is not good
寝すぎてもダメだよ
But what is his detailed mechanism
しかし、彼の詳細なメカニズムは何ですか
I'm actually not quite sure what they are
実際のところ、それらが何なのかよくわかりません
i think they do pop research
彼らはポップスの研究をしていると思う
epidemiological research
疫学調査
Indeed, I personally don't really believe that it has something to do with the brain.
確かに、個人的にはそれが脳とは何の関係もないと信じています。
There are other functions of other bodies
他の身体には他の機能がある
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
Mad Cow Syndrome
狂牛病症候群
I don’t dare to eat a certain kind of beef casually, do I?
気軽に牛肉を食べる勇気はありませんよね？
That's the Pryon we were talking about
それが私たちが話していたプリオンです
This is actually the principle of plaque formation
実はこれがプラーク形成の原理なのです
Later, people like Shi Zhizheng used this principle
その後、施志正のような人々がこの原理を使用しました。
So in fact it has some principles that are very similar
実際、非常によく似た原則がいくつかあります
thank you teacher for your speech
先生、ご講演ありがとうございました
Excuse me, is that the antibody?
すみません、それは抗体ですか？
What is the role? Is it an anti-inflammatory drug?
役割は何ですか? 抗炎症薬ですか?
It was also mentioned recently that
最近も話題になりましたが、
Parenchyma actually has something to do with some inflammation in our brain
実際、実質は脳内の炎症に関連しています。
I would like to ask, because the teacher just mentioned that
今先生がおっしゃったので伺いたいのですが。
Uh, if you inhale the medicine from the nasal cavity
えー、鼻腔から薬を吸うと
Then if we use an anti-inflammatory drug inhaled from the nasal cavity
次に、鼻腔から吸入する抗炎症薬を使用すると、
Could it also be for some inflammation in the brain?
脳内の炎症も考えられますか？
and then make some improvements
そしていくつかの改善を加えます
Then the second question is that
それから 2 番目の質問は、
Uh, it was mentioned that it was during sleep
ああ、寝ている間だと言われました
The brain and spine can help us clear the lungs from the brain
脳と脊椎は脳から肺を取り除くのに役立ちます
What about a nap, a Technap
昼寝はどうですか、テクナップ
a question
質問
Masquerading as two questions? Yeah?
2 つの質問を装っているのですか? そうですか?
i will forget later you have to remind me
後で忘れてしまうので、思い出させてください
Just, uh, taking a nap is actually pretty good for me personally.
ただ、えー、昼寝は個人的にはかなり良いことなんです。
Because you imagine it, don't think it's complicated
想像するから複雑なことは考えないでください
Just imagine, it clears the lungs
想像してみてください、肺がきれいになります
so take a nap every once in a while and make it work
だから時々昼寝して仕事をしましょう
I'm actually surprised to say, like we're sitting here, you know you're
私たちがここに座っているように、あなたがそうであることを知っていると言うのは実際には驚いています
your row you hardly row 95%
あなたの漕ぎはほとんど漕げない 95%
You are
あなたは
So basically when I take a nap once in a while
だから基本的に、たまに昼寝するときは
In fact, it should be a good effect.
実際、良い効果が得られるはずです。
then we just
それから私たちはただ
I don't know if it's my classmates who look very young
クラスメイトがとても若く見えるかどうかはわかりません
i think this
私はこう思います
make me feel so comforted today
今日は私をとても慰めてくれます
that's why you came
だからあなたは来たのです
Talk and interact with everyone
みんなと話したり交流したりする
because maybe we could exchange some ideas
もしかしたらいくつかのアイデアを交換できるかもしれないから
nothing wrong nothing wrong
何も問題ありません何も問題ありません
That is, if there are some anti-inflammatory drugs
つまり、抗炎症薬があれば
It can enter through the nasal cavity, can it develop?
鼻腔から侵入する可能性がありますが、発症する可能性はありますか?
We first did another
最初に別のことをしました
is a small protein
小さなタンパク質です
We have also considered the possibility
という可能性も検討しました
I think its biggest difficulty is
その最大の難点は、
Not difficult. The biggest hesitation is
難しいことではありませんが、最大の躊躇は
in the end people
結局人は
Because this piece stands very small
この作品はとても小さいので、
does it work well
うまくいきますか
So this I think at present
それで、現時点で私はこう考えています
not very sure
よくわからない
but
しかし
Vodin is the evil teeth are very good
Vodin は邪悪な歯がとても良いです
So many people use this aspect
非常に多くの人がこの側面を使用しています
It's good to have a question just now
今すぐ質問していただいて結構です
That is to say, is it possible that this antibody
つまり、この抗体は可能性がありますか？
also anti-inflammatory
抗炎症作用もあります
in what we mentioned today
今日話した内容の中で
Instructor, these two antibodies are not anti-inflammatory
教官、これら 2 つの抗体は抗炎症作用がありません
He is scratching the plaque off
彼はプラークを引っ掻いて剥がしている
make him clear better
彼の気持ちをはっきりさせて
But what?
でも何？
Some Drugs I Know Are Paranormal
私が知っているいくつかの薬物は超常現象です
Some people really want to use antibodies to fight inflammation
炎症と戦うために抗体を本当に使いたい人もいます
If you have participated in the Academia Sinica Hall Award
中央研究院賞に参加したことがある方
will know
わかるでしょう
They also hope that they can throw in protein
彼らはまた、プロテインを投入できることを望んでいます
And then make some essence change out?
そして、本質を変えてみませんか？
So in fact the biggest difficulty is
実際のところ、最大の難点は、
I think it's blood brain
血液脳だと思う
Obstacles
障害物
there is
がある
is to put protein in
プロテインを入れることです
Or do you need to use a certain virus
それとも特定のウイルスを使用する必要がありますか
Will the virus cause other problems later on?
ウイルスは後で別の問題を引き起こすのでしょうか?
in this way
この上
Hello, teacher
こんにちは先生
Just looking at some supplementary information
補足情報をいくつか見てみると、
he said that
彼はそう言いました
It is CHA repeat
チャリピートです
In fact, it seems to be one of his goals in evolution
実際、それは彼の進化における目標の 1 つであるようです
that is
あれは
like
好き
like in fact to a certain extent
実際にある程度そうであるように
If he has a high CGP
CGPが高い場合
He's a guy who might get smarter or something
彼はもっと賢くなるかもしれない男だ
So I wonder if it will be us humans
それで私たち人間になるのかな
This is an evolutionary trend
これは進化の傾向です
is that we may be destined to become like this
私たちはこうなる運命なのかもしれないということ
this question is really good
この質問は本当に良いです
what he asked was
彼が尋ねたのは
Repeat of this CG
このCGの繰り返し
Is it really bad to be long?
本当に長いのはダメなのでしょうか？
Will he be an evolutionary question
彼は進化論的な質問になるだろうか
I think what you say makes sense
あなたの言うことは一理あると思います
Because there is a team in Italy
イタリアにチームがあるので
just do this
ただこれをしてください
their conclusion is
彼らの結論は
This CGP is related to nerves
このCGPは神経に関係しています
on this gene
この遺伝子について
It is very important for the differentiation and development of nerves
神経の分化と発達にとって非常に重要です
so
それで
so you know those
だからあなたはそれらを知っています
because we know some patients
私たちは何人かの患者を知っているので
Honey is really sick
ハニーは本当に病気です
actually usually
実際には通常
These patients are all good-looking
この患者さんたちはみんなイケメンです
smart when young
若い頃は賢い
full of energy
活力に満ちた
They even did a real survey
彼らは実際の調査も行いました
Find these kids in America
アメリカでこの子供たちを見つけてください
before the age of 18
18歳になる前に
Their homework follows the rules
彼らの宿題はルールに従っています
follow that rule
そのルールに従ってください
better than average kids
平均的な子供たちよりも優れている
but unfortunately he arrived
しかし残念ながら彼は到着しました
He became ill at the age of forty or fifty
彼は40歳か50歳で病気になった
so come back
だから戻ってきて
i totally agree with what you said
私はあなたの言うことに完全に同意します
just in evolution
まさに進化の途中
The length of your fart actually has his purpose
あなたのオナラの長さには、実は彼の目的があるのです
But when he gets too out of control
しかし、彼が制御不能になりすぎると、
he will cause serious problems
彼は深刻な問題を引き起こすだろう
Come
来て
host
ホスト
Professor Chen
チェン教授
grateful
感謝
Professor Chen is very exciting tonight
今夜はチェン先生がとてもエキサイティングです
give us that speech
私たちにそのスピーチをしてください
I join the Sunshine Academy
サンシャインアカデミーに入学します
two or three years
2、3年
we are in the middle
私たちは真ん中にいる
us
私たち
There are many elderly people here who may be very concerned.
ここには心配している高齢者がたくさんいます。
old sir old brother like me
私と同じようなお兄さん
My ball will be 80 soon this year
私のボールは今年もうすぐ80になります
congratulations congratulations awesome
おめでとう、おめでとう、すごいね
I hope the fire gets older
火が古くなることを願っています
Han Chuan said that the longer the fire, the more you will get. Come on!
ハン・チュアンは、火が長ければ長いほど、より多くのものが得られると言いました。
Ha ha ha ha
ハハハッハッハ
After listening to Professor Chen's original lecture
陳教授のオリジナル講義を聞いた後
We know that
私達はことを知っています
community of spirits working together
協力する精霊たちのコミュニティ
ah
ああ
It's hard to understand
わかりにくいです
because of U.S
米国のせいで
common wisdom
常識
Although a large
大きいですが、
hard work
大変な仕事
but
しかし
Wenmeng Particles
文夢の粒子
For example Gan disease
例えばガン病
Gan disease
ガン病
also the same
また同じです
Gan pregnant until now
ガンは今まで妊娠中
there is no way to overcome
克服する方法はありません
and this heart attack
そして今回の心臓発作
no way
とんでもない
and this
この
with visceral cancer
内臓がんがある
electric man
電動人
today
今日
be honest about this
これについては正直に言ってください
old nervous disease
古い神経疾患
like electric man
電気人間みたいに
Or wear a needle
もしくは針を付けるとか
Your daughter, we all work together, there is nothing wrong
あなたの娘さん、私たちは皆で協力します、何も問題ありません
I celebrate the new year, in fact, I also announced the new year
私は新年を祝います、実際、私は新年の発表もしました
In other words, I want to be a good person, good intentions will be rewarded, and I can come
言い換えれば、私は良い人になりたい、善意は報われる、そして私は来ることができます
We old people want three more times, be happy psychologically, and have a happy new year
私たち老人はあと 3 回、精神的に幸せになり、良い新年を迎えたいと思っています
It is very important to be healthy
健康であることはとても大切です
Many old people retreated and died soon after
多くの老人が撤退してすぐに亡くなった
In short, Meng didn't get much, so he hung up. It's a pity.
つまり、孟氏はあまり得られなかったので、電話を切りました。
what should i do
私は何をすべきか
The body must be healthy, and the mood must be relaxed
体は健康で、気分もリラックスしている必要があります
Be in a very healthy mood, or there will be more
非常に健康的な気分でいること、そうでない場合はさらに多くのことが起こります
there's nothing we can do here
ここで私たちにできることは何もありません
be happy
幸せになる
don't be angry all the time
いつも怒らないでください
besides
そのほか
To be active
アクティブになるために
to move more
もっと動くために
exercise more
多運動
Swim for an hour every morning
毎朝1時間泳ぐ
half an hour
30分
i have worked hard
私は一生懸命働きました
Can you get a master?
マスターを取得できますか？
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
be healthy
健康になる
happy heart
幸せな心
to overcome
克服するために
our old man is sick
私たちの老人は病気です
Le's work hard
ルちゃん頑張ってね
Thank you Pope Chen
陳教皇に感謝します
our great speech
私たちの素晴らしいスピーチ
Thanks
ありがとう
I thank you very much
ありがとうございます
I start the day by thanking you the most for being here
ここに来てくれた皆さんに感謝して一日を始めます
And I'm very thankful for today's question
そして、今日の質問には本当に感謝しています
Because this is one of us all
これは私たち全員の一人だから
opportunity for discussion
議論の機会
Our Dean Le recently said something
私たちのディーン・リーが最近こんなことを言いました
words that touch me personally
個人的に心に響く言葉
He said that the researchers of our Central Plains Academy
彼は、私たちのセントラル・プレーンズ・アカデミーの研究者たちはこう言いました。
What should be done is long and heavy
やるべきことは長くて重い
real
本物
may contribute
貢献するかもしれない
Maybe I still don't contribute much until I retire
もしかしたら引退するまではまだあまり貢献できないかもしれない
but
しかし
like you just said
あなたが今言ったように
We can't solve a lot
多くのことは解決できません
We haven't resolved what you just mentioned
あなたが今言ったことはまだ解決していません
but our
しかし私たちの
Has life been extended
寿命は延びたのか
Have it
それを持っている
We can handle a lot of ailments now
今では多くの病気に対処できるようになりました
I personally believe
私は個人的に信じています
Give our research people a little more time
研究担当者にもう少し時間を与えてください
there is a chance
チャンスはある
And we're not saying wish to live very old
そして私たちは、長生きしたいと言っているのではありません
we want to live healthy
私たちは健康に生きたいです
so we'll do it
だからやってみよう
I am adding a question
質問を追加しています
that is
あれは
How to keep our old nerves alive and healthy
古い神経を生かして健康に保つ方法
I need to use my brain more after reading it
読んだ後はもっと頭を使う必要がある
So I can still write tasks
それでまだタスクを書くことができます
write a report
レポートを書きます
no problem
問題ない
I'm going to keep more
もっと保管しておきます
This Buddha can't rest with one mind
この仏は一心では休めない
keep moving
動き続ける
great
素晴らしい
Thanks
ありがとう
I think those who are here today, of course you will not get substantive evidence
今日ここに来ている人たちは、もちろん誰も実質的な証拠を手に入れることはできないと思います
Thank you, I want to ask a question, and a comment about one thing
ありがとう、一つ質問とコメントがしたいのですが
You just mentioned that what is clear is that we have to pass that thing, we have to learn from old obstacles
あなたは今、明らかなことは、古い障害から学ぶために、私たちはそれを乗り越えなければならないということだと言いました
Then go inside, go into the part of the heart student
それから中に入って、心の部分に入ってください。
When we want to be clear, will he also be sent out from the old barrier
はっきりさせたいときは、彼も古い障壁から追い出されるのだろうか
Sending off after studies, is this the way to go
放課後お見送り、これでいいの？
In that case, he is entering the 0.8 billion
その場合、彼は8億ドルに入る
After entering, you still have to pass through the old barrier to get out
入った後も、外に出るには古い学校の障壁を通過する必要があります
No, he is, he has convection, he first convects cerebral fluid and hydrocephalus fluid
いいえ、彼は対流を持っています、彼は最初に脳液と水頭症液を対流させます
Then it went out with 0.8 billion, and after going out
それから8億で出て行って、出て行った後は
It will be dealt with in other systems that will be upgraded
アップグレードされる他のシステムで対処される予定です
So he no longer passes the old age barrier
だから彼はもう老後の壁を越えない
In the example we just mentioned, it will not
先ほど述べた例では、そうではありません。
ok, ok, ok, understand, thank you
わかりました、わかりました、わかりました、ありがとう
Then I have another comment, which is aimed at just now
それからもう一つコメントがありますが、それは今のことを目的としています
someone asked
誰かが尋ねた
sport, sorry, i teach at model university
スポーツ、申し訳ありませんが、私はモデル大学で教えています
I do sports nutrition, wow, great, no
私はスポーツ栄養学をやっています、すごい、すごい、いいえ
Then I suggest that now it's about sports
それなら今度はスポーツの話だと提案します
In animal studies, that is just now
動物実験ではそれが今です
You give the mouse the running, the roller
あなたはマウスとローラーを動かします
They did research and found something like that, the scroll wheel
彼らは調査を行った結果、スクロールホイールというものを発見しました。
The point is the position of its footsteps
ポイントは足音の位置
There are many sports, each with its own advantages
スポーツにはたくさんの種類があり、それぞれに独自の利点があります
That's like swimming for cardiorespiratory fitness
それは心肺機能を高めるために水泳するようなものです
What about running, because gradually hitting the ground
ランニングはどうでしょうか。一歩ずつ地面を蹴るので、
This power of this impact
このインパクトのこのパワー
or whatever it is , better not run
それが何であれ、走らないほうがいいです
and everyone because of knee problems
そしてみんな膝の問題のために
go, go, go
行って、行って、見て行って
Then that step by step by accepting the stimulation of the ground
そして地面の刺激を受け入れて一歩ずつ
Then this part will stimulate the real body of your mouse nerve
次に、この部分がラットの神経の本体を刺激します。
can increase your mouse nerve body
マウスの神経体を増やすことができます
Can make a lot of tissue that can repair some nerves
一部の神経を修復できる組織を大量に作ることができる
In animal experiments, in human experiments have found some
動物実験や人体実験でいくつかのことがわかっています。
some time like a professional person
いつかプロの人のように
They stimulated his feet like this
彼らはこうやって彼の足を刺激した
stimulate his feet
彼の足を刺激する
Using this will help his nerves recover
これを使うと神経が回復する
Of course it may not be fully recovered
もちろん完全には回復しないかもしれませんが、
But the feet will have this benefit
しかし、足にはこの利点があります
Therefore, there are divisions in the heart of sports
したがって、スポーツの中心部には分裂が存在します
have different effects
さまざまな効果があります
it does have
それはあります
And for osteoporosis each has its own benefits
骨粗鬆症にはそれぞれ独自の利点があります
provide reference thanks
参考にさせていただきます、よろしくお願いします
That palm you just mentioned
あなたが今言ったあの手のひら
do you want to eat your feet
足を食べたいですか？
eat a foot
足を食べる
But afraid of contamination, infection and injury
でも汚染、感染、怪我が怖い
So wear better shoes
だからもっと良い靴を履いてください
better protect yourself
もっと自分を守ったほうがいい
And the tendon walk is not the hand
そして腱ウォークは手ではありません
is this two hands is going to
この両手はそうなるのですか
bring it up
それを持ち出す
stick to this place
この場所に固執する
like this
このような
To be like this is not to fall like this
こうなるということは、このように堕落することではない
so there are some
だからいくつかあります
And where his feet are
そして彼の足はどこにあるのか
Step on it like this
こうやって踏んでいく
this way is
この道は
Just stepped on the heel and foot again like this
こうやってまたかかとと足を踏んだだけです
So I hope to touch my feet more
だから私はもっと足に触れたいと思っています
Do a little and provide a reference
少しやってみて参考にしてください
Le's work hard
ルちゃん頑張ってね
I will take your push in two more months
あと2か月後、あなたの背中を押してください
So do you feel that you should listen to speeches more in the future, right?
では、今後はもっとスピーチを聞いたほうがいいと思いますよね？
We have so many learned people in our audience
聴衆には学識のある人がたくさんいます
really good
とてもいいです
ask the professor
教授に聞く
I saw the profile of the host here.
ここでホストのプロフィールを見ました。
Research team combines advances in Chinese herbal medicine
研究チームは漢方薬の進歩を融合
research biopharmaceuticals
バイオ医薬品の研究
Then a new drug adenosic acid was developed to treat neurodegenerative diseases
その後、神経変性疾患を治療するための新薬アデノシン酸が開発されました。
In fact, new drugs are already being researched.
実際、新薬はすでに研究されています。
Anyway, it was developed.
とにかく開発されました。
It should have been developed in the past
昔に開発されてたはず
I don't know how the progress of this new drug is going.
この新薬の進歩がどのように進んでいるのかわかりません。
what is expected
何が期待されているのか
in development
開発中
middle
中
That process is so long
そのプロセスはとても長いです
The process of a new drug takes about 17 years
新薬の誕生には約17年かかる
That's because there are many
それはたくさんあるからです
It's not a matter of science anymore
それはもう科学の問題ではない
So we just hoped for the best
だから私たちはただ最高の結果を望んでいた
Let's transfer the notes first
まずはメモを転送しましょう
then we wish to say
それから私たちは言いたいのです
he is in the next stage
彼は次の段階にいる
Because there are still many human experiments
まだ人体実験がたくさんあるから
This is why we also
だからこそ私たちも
Recent efforts to develop biomarkers
バイオマーカー開発への最近の取り組み
because there is medicine
薬があるから
You are a manufacturer
あなたはメーカーです
He refused to take medicine for five years
彼は5年間薬の服用を拒否した
because he thinks it's too expensive
彼はそれが高すぎると思うから
If we find good biomarkers
良いバイオマーカーが見つかったら
maybe there will be a chance
もしかしたらチャンスがあるかもしれない
research herbal medicine
漢方薬を研究する
Chinese herbal medicine
漢方薬
our drug
私たちの薬
It is found from Chinese herbal medicine
漢方薬からわかる
Then we combine
それから組み合わせます
Is the professor of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学の教授です
specialized in chemical modifications
化学修飾に特化した
find new drugs
新しい薬を見つける
So at the beginning we were
それで、最初は私たちは
Talk about Chinese herbal medicine
漢方薬についての話
Because the older ones often have a lot of wisdom
年上の人は知恵が豊富な人が多いので
so we came out of there
それで私たちはそこから出てきました
so what i'm talking about
それで私が話していることは
This is actually a group of drugs
これは実際には麻薬のグループです
That's what we do from Chinese herbal medicine to synthetic
それが私たちが漢方薬から合成まで行っていることです
and then to the animal
そして動物の中へ
and then in the already present already turned
そして、すでに現在にすでに変わっています
we're going to keep going like this
私たちはこのまま続けます
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you for my speech today
今日はスピーチをありがとうございました
i want to ask
聞きたいです
Why do our brains
なぜ私たちの脳は
why would
なぜだろう
What is the inflammatory reaction?
炎症反応とは何ですか?
why on earth
なぜ地球上で
Then I wondered if research would
それから、研究はできるだろうかと思いました。
Gradually study that encirclement cell
徐々にその包囲細胞を研究する
Is it because of the inflammation?
炎症のせいでしょうか？
Then I read in the book that there are two types of siege cells
それから、本で読んだのですが、包囲細胞には 2 種類あるとのことです。
what do you mean
どういう意味
You mean active and inactive
アクティブと非アクティブを意味します
I don't know what the two types are
その２種類が何なのかは分かりませんが、
in this way
この上
right
右
That
それか
Actually I don't know why it's inflamed
実際のところ、なぜ炎症を起こしているのかはわかりません
Because the brain
なぜなら、脳は
you see we are
私たちがいるのがわかりますか
Creation of heaven and earth
天地造物
Look how good our brain masks are
私たちのブレインマスクがどれほど優れているか見てください
It's actually not very susceptible to external infections
実は外部からの感染にはあまり弱いのです
except for a few
一部を除いて
virus or something
ウイルスか何か
So it's actually not very infected
つまり、実際にはそれほど感染していません
when you were older
あなたが年上のとき
Infected
感染した
It is inflammation that often occurs
よく起こる炎症です
that sometimes
それは時々
I personally guess
私は推測する
It's because it's been used for a long time
長く使われているものだから
So some things like
それで、次のようなものがあります
Not too light
軽すぎない
Or some cells are slowly dying
あるいは一部の細胞がゆっくりと死んでいく
dying nerve cells
死にかけている神経細胞
deactivates encirclement cells
包囲細胞を非活性化する
they become overly inflamed
彼らは過度に炎症を起こします
Not to mention there are some
言うまでもなくいくつかあります
For example, genetic diseases, etc.
例えば、遺伝性疾患などです。
So speeches often follow
したがって、スピーチが続くことがよくあります
is the age
年齢は
Aging itself is related
老化そのものが関係している
But at present Shi Zhizheng's biggest factor
しかし、現時点で石志正の最大の要因は
actually age
実際の年齢
so we really have to take care of ourselves
だから私たちは本当に自分自身の世話をしなければなりません
don't stay up late talking
夜更かしして話さないでください
yes
はい
ask the teacher
先生に尋ねる
Neurodegeneration including Shi Zhizheng
Shi Zhizheng を含む神経変性
in different human societies
さまざまな人間社会で
Is there such a phenomenon in the human period and society?
人間の時代や社会にそのような現象はあるのでしょうか？
Animals other than humans
人間以外の動物
Is it easy to have this kind of neurodegeneration in old age?
高齢になるとこの種の神経変性が起こりやすいのでしょうか？
Is his degenerated physiological mechanism the same as that of human beings?
彼の退化した生理メカニズムは人間と同じなのでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
I came a while ago with one of my friends and it was Rotation
しばらく前に友達の一人と来ました、そしてそれはローテーションでした
Just do the content of the short-term training first
まずは短期研修の内容をこなすだけ
Chat with students in Gilead
ギリアドの学生とチャットする
Neurodegeneration has never been studied in their country
神経変性は彼らの国では研究されたことがありません
why
なぜ
They are nervous that their lifespan is 50 years old
彼らは自分たちの寿命が50歳であることに不安を感じています
no degradation
劣化なし
Too late to degenerate
退化するには遅すぎる
We look at the great heroes of the ancient road
古道の偉大な英雄たちを見てみましょう
How old were they all when they died?
彼らは全員何歳で亡くなりましたか?
Thirty or forty?
30人か40人か？
I read Jin Yong's novels one day and want to say
ある日、金庸の小説を読んでこう言いたいです。
Wow
おお
50 years old
50歳
It's Laoqu
ラオクーです
people from different eras
さまざまな時代の人々
rarely like our time
私たちの時代のようなことはめったにありません
live so long
とても長生きする
That's why degradation becomes a serious problem
だからこそ劣化が深刻な問題になる
Same situation in the US
アメリカでも同じ状況
they are not as serious as us
彼らは私たちほど真剣ではありません
Our childishness and aging and Japan
私たちの幼さと老いと日本
are serious countries
深刻な国です
no america
アメリカはありません
But they also saw that when the country
しかし、彼らもまた、この国が
when the culture is at its peak
文化が最高潮に達したとき
this is becoming a
これはになりつつあります
A situation that has never been encountered before
これまでに経験したことのない状況
That's why this kind of research came out
だからこそこのような研究が出てきたのです
That
それか
most of the animals i know
私が知っている動物のほとんどは
Not as good as class
クラスほど良くない
It seems that no one has degenerated
誰も退化していないようだ
It's our degeneration
それは私たちの退化です
It seems like even a monkey, right Mr. Chen
まるで猿のようですね、チェンさん
monkeys are
猿は
monkeys don't degenerate
猿は退化しない
So we are using
それで私たちは使っています
When this animal model
この動物モデルが
really very disturbing
本当にとても不安です
right
右
if not now
今でなければ
We thank Mr. Chen today
今日はチェンさんに感謝します
very good speech
とても良いスピーチ
Thank you for giving me this opportunity
この機会を与えてくれてありがとう
thank you all for coming tonight
今夜来てくれてありがとう
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました